[
    {
        "text": "Out of desperation, he and Victra secretly meet with Adrius au Augustus, commonly known as \"The Jackal,\" in the Lost City on Luna.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 27,
                "end": 33,
                "text": "Victra"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 53,
                "end": 71,
                "text": "Adrius au Augustus"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 96,
                "end": 102,
                "text": "Jackal"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 112,
                "end": 121,
                "text": "Lost City"
            },
            {
                "label": "Planet",
                "start": 125,
                "end": 129,
                "text": "Luna"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Ragnar is confused and convinced he is being tricked.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Ragnar"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "After beating him badly, Karnus tells him that his actions against house Bellona will not go unanswered - his Mother wants Darrow's heart.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 25,
                "end": 31,
                "text": "Karnus"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 67,
                "end": 80,
                "text": "house Bellona"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 123,
                "end": 131,
                "text": "Darrow's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "The rest of his old retinue has been scattered across the solar system, notably Sevro and the Howlers who have been sent to far orbit, and Mustang who has taken up politics on Luna.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 80,
                "end": 85,
                "text": "Sevro"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 94,
                "end": 101,
                "text": "Howlers"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 139,
                "end": 146,
                "text": "Mustang"
            },
            {
                "label": "Planet",
                "start": 176,
                "end": 180,
                "text": "Luna"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Lysander finally meets Atlas au Raa upon his fifth time in the torture chains.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 8,
                "text": "Lysander"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 23,
                "end": 35,
                "text": "Atlas au Raa"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "When Darrow enters it, he quickly realizes it's booby-trapped, as others have warned, but he's able to deactivate the rest of the traps.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 5,
                "end": 11,
                "text": "Darrow"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "To wage and win the war that will change humankindâ€™s destiny, Darrow must confront the treachery arrayed against him, overcome his all-too-human desire for retributionâ€”and strive not for violent revolt but a hopeful rebirth.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 60,
                "end": 66,
                "text": "Darrow"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Exeter and Glirastes' remaining lowColor staff pledge fealty to Lysander.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Exeter"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 11,
                "end": 20,
                "text": "Glirastes"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 32,
                "end": 40,
                "text": "lowColor"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 64,
                "end": 72,
                "text": "Lysander"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Upon urging from Victra, Roque gives a farewell kiss on both Darrowâ€™s cheeks.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 17,
                "end": 23,
                "text": "Victra"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 25,
                "end": 30,
                "text": "Roque"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 61,
                "end": 69,
                "text": "Darrowâ€™s"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Returning to the Gala, Darrow marches straight to the Bellona table, jumps on top and walks through dinner plates to where Cassius sits.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 23,
                "end": 29,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 54,
                "end": 61,
                "text": "Bellona"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 123,
                "end": 130,
                "text": "Cassius"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "When Darrow is conscious again, a week has passed.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 5,
                "end": 11,
                "text": "Darrow"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "However, Lysander surprises her with an offer of an alliance in marriage.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 9,
                "end": 17,
                "text": "Lysander"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Darrow admits he is a red and Sevro says that he was shown the carving when he met with Dancer.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "Caste",
                "start": 22,
                "end": 25,
                "text": "red"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 30,
                "end": 35,
                "text": "Sevro"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 88,
                "end": 94,
                "text": "Dancer"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Fig, the unusual Brown that took Lyria from Virginia's home escorts her out of the room one day, stating that Ephraim has arranged for her and Volga's release.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 3,
                "text": "Fig"
            },
            {
                "label": "Caste",
                "start": 17,
                "end": 22,
                "text": "Brown"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 33,
                "end": 38,
                "text": "Lyria"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 44,
                "end": 54,
                "text": "Virginia's"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 110,
                "end": 117,
                "text": "Ephraim"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 143,
                "end": 150,
                "text": "Volga's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "They don't go back to the Citadel, but go in search for Victra.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 26,
                "end": 33,
                "text": "Citadel"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 56,
                "end": 62,
                "text": "Victra"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Also part of the Reaper's counter-ambush are the small bombs he secretly placed as he first entered the Garden.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 17,
                "end": 25,
                "text": "Reaper's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Nero agrees and the duel begins.",
        "mentions": []
    },
    {
        "text": "Darrow also sees Cassius, who has been made the Morning Knight - one of the Soveriegns' Olympic Knights.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 17,
                "end": 24,
                "text": "Cassius"
            },
            {
                "label": "Rank",
                "start": 48,
                "end": 62,
                "text": "Morning Knight"
            },
            {
                "label": "Rank",
                "start": 76,
                "end": 86,
                "text": "Soveriegns"
            },
            {
                "label": "Rank",
                "start": 88,
                "end": 103,
                "text": "Olympic Knights"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "That night, Cicero suggests killing the Grays since he's sure they'll run out of water before they reach the closest city, Erebos, but Lysander refuses.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 12,
                "end": 18,
                "text": "Cicero"
            },
            {
                "label": "Caste",
                "start": 40,
                "end": 45,
                "text": "Grays"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 123,
                "end": 129,
                "text": "Erebos"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 135,
                "end": 143,
                "text": "Lysander"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "She plans on becoming the Sovereign, and plans to kill Lysander for it.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Rank",
                "start": 26,
                "end": 35,
                "text": "Sovereign"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 55,
                "end": 63,
                "text": "Lysander"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Roque was able to capture more than eighty percent of the Bellona fleet, making his own larger than Darrow's.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 56,
                "end": 63,
                "text": "Bellona"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 98,
                "end": 106,
                "text": "Darrow's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "But the Society he faithfully served was built on lies.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 8,
                "end": 15,
                "text": "Society"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Lysander doesn't have anything against him, but when Apollonius offers his help, Lysander refuses, not wanting to be indebted to him.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 8,
                "text": "Lysander"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 53,
                "end": 63,
                "text": "Apollonius"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 81,
                "end": 89,
                "text": "Lysander"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "All in attendance seem to just be waiting for Darrow to lay out the next step.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 46,
                "end": 52,
                "text": "Darrow"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "The city revolts against Darrow and his men.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 25,
                "end": 31,
                "text": "Darrow"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "After further observation, they can't find any reason to not believe Cato's story, so they allow Glirastes and Cato to reunite.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 69,
                "end": 75,
                "text": "Cato's"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 97,
                "end": 106,
                "text": "Glirastes"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 111,
                "end": 115,
                "text": "Cato"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "But Cassius au Bellona arrives, giving Darrow hope.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 4,
                "end": 22,
                "text": "Cassius au Bellona"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 39,
                "end": 45,
                "text": "Darrow"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Publius and the Vox Populi shout tyranny and it becomes a coup, with many people and senators killed.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 7,
                "text": "Publius"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 16,
                "end": 26,
                "text": "Vox Populi"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Confident with his odds, Darrow moves in for the kill, but is surprised when a second ship slips through his lines and rams his, devastating Darrow's flagship.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 25,
                "end": 31,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 141,
                "end": 149,
                "text": "Darrow's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "They attempt to kill him on Ajax's order.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 28,
                "end": 34,
                "text": "Ajax's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Harmony offers Darrow a chance to help them.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 7,
                "text": "Harmony"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 15,
                "end": 21,
                "text": "Darrow"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Sefi at first denies him as her father, but as he continues to speak and reveal memories, as well as a broken amulet of a griffin, the Alltribe, especially the males, slowly start being convinced.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 4,
                "text": "Sefi"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 135,
                "end": 143,
                "text": "Alltribe"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "As they continue on their path to Erebos, they stop near a hydra burrow, careful not to get too close for fear of a bush hydra coming out of the hole.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 34,
                "end": 40,
                "text": "Erebos"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Once they land on the ship, the Love Knight, Kalindora au San, who Lysander thought dead, and Ajax meet them skeptically.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Rank",
                "start": 32,
                "end": 43,
                "text": "Love Knight"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 45,
                "end": 61,
                "text": "Kalindora au San"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 67,
                "end": 75,
                "text": "Lysander"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 94,
                "end": 98,
                "text": "Ajax"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "On his way back to Eagle Rest from a walk around the city, Ephraim sees on someone's datapad that the Pandora has been attacked.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 19,
                "end": 29,
                "text": "Eagle Rest"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 59,
                "end": 66,
                "text": "Ephraim"
            },
            {
                "label": "Vehicle",
                "start": 102,
                "end": 109,
                "text": "Pandora"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Darrow sends Ragnar and the other Obsidians, all now Razor armed, to attack the back of the wall and open the gates for the outside forces.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 13,
                "end": 19,
                "text": "Ragnar"
            },
            {
                "label": "Caste",
                "start": 34,
                "end": 43,
                "text": "Obsidians"
            },
            {
                "label": "Weapon",
                "start": 53,
                "end": 58,
                "text": "Razor"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "After Volga has left, Pax lets Lyria know that his mother is still alive.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 6,
                "end": 11,
                "text": "Volga"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 22,
                "end": 25,
                "text": "Pax"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 31,
                "end": 36,
                "text": "Lyria"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "During the cleanup of the beach, Darrow gave a Razor to Ragnar.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 33,
                "end": 39,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "Weapon",
                "start": 47,
                "end": 52,
                "text": "Razor"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 56,
                "end": 62,
                "text": "Ragnar"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Victra lets Volga go to the transmitter in the town to send a message to Victra's troops to come get them.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Victra"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 12,
                "end": 17,
                "text": "Volga"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 73,
                "end": 81,
                "text": "Victra's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "With their only protection now gone, and time running out for everyone, Darrow again his failed stunt from he Acadamy.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 72,
                "end": 78,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "MISC",
                "start": 110,
                "end": 117,
                "text": "Acadamy"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Atlas and Atalantia also had allied with Lilath, but they don't know about the Abomination.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 5,
                "text": "Atlas"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 10,
                "end": 19,
                "text": "Atalantia"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 41,
                "end": 47,
                "text": "Lilath"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 79,
                "end": 90,
                "text": "Abomination"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Surprised to see her old friend, she takes this chance to remove Darrow from the area, revealing that bombs have been planted in the area, targeting the Jackal.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 65,
                "end": 71,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 153,
                "end": 159,
                "text": "Jackal"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Victra gives birth with Lyria watching.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Victra"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 24,
                "end": 29,
                "text": "Lyria"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "He puts her body with all the other bodies that were retrieved from the water.",
        "mentions": []
    },
    {
        "text": "When he reaches Erebos, he finds the city underwater, totally destroyed.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 16,
                "end": 22,
                "text": "Erebos"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "A decade-long peace still exists between the Republic and the Golds of the Rim worlds, but something stirs in the darkness out beyond the asteroid belt.[2]",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 45,
                "end": 53,
                "text": "Republic"
            },
            {
                "label": "Caste",
                "start": 62,
                "end": 67,
                "text": "Golds"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 75,
                "end": 78,
                "text": "Rim"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 138,
                "end": 151,
                "text": "asteroid belt"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Victra seems to know about the parasite, but doesn't say anything to Volga.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Victra"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 69,
                "end": 74,
                "text": "Volga"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Alexandar survives the surgery.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 9,
                "text": "Alexandar"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "The escape craft crashes in Cimmeria.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 28,
                "end": 36,
                "text": "Cimmeria"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "However, he and those with him, including Thraxa au Telemanus, Alexandar au Arcos, Colloway xe Char, Tongueless, and his niece Rhonna, attempt a rescue of one of his most loyal, Orion xe Aquarii, from the ship the Blood Medusa.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 42,
                "end": 61,
                "text": "Thraxa au Telemanus"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 63,
                "end": 81,
                "text": "Alexandar au Arcos"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 83,
                "end": 99,
                "text": "Colloway xe Char"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 101,
                "end": 111,
                "text": "Tongueless"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 127,
                "end": 133,
                "text": "Rhonna"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 178,
                "end": 194,
                "text": "Orion xe Aquarii"
            },
            {
                "label": "Vehicle",
                "start": 214,
                "end": 226,
                "text": "Blood Medusa"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Virginia is brought to a banquet for the jackals, seated next to the Abomination.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 8,
                "text": "Virginia"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 41,
                "end": 48,
                "text": "jackals"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 69,
                "end": 80,
                "text": "Abomination"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Given only a few days notice rather than the traditional months, the move both destroys any power and clout Darrow may have held and removes all the protections afforded to him by House Augustus.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 108,
                "end": 114,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 180,
                "end": 194,
                "text": "House Augustus"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "He tells them he is Cato au Vetruvius, and Alexandar introduces the rest of them as the Knights of Elysium - Drusilla, Ignacius, Crastus, and Hadrian.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 20,
                "end": 37,
                "text": "Cato au Vetruvius"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 43,
                "end": 52,
                "text": "Alexandar"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 109,
                "end": 117,
                "text": "Drusilla"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 119,
                "end": 127,
                "text": "Ignacius"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 129,
                "end": 136,
                "text": "Crastus"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 142,
                "end": 149,
                "text": "Hadrian"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 88,
                "end": 106,
                "text": "Knights of Elysium"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "They set a hologram in front of her to watch the execution of Theodora and Servilla au Arcos, as well as her Lionguard, and other people who were likely going to vote for her.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 62,
                "end": 70,
                "text": "Theodora"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 75,
                "end": 92,
                "text": "Servilla au Arcos"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 109,
                "end": 118,
                "text": "Lionguard"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "The Jackal has been expanding his power since the Institute and is now in control of a sizeable percentage of the Core's media networks.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 4,
                "end": 10,
                "text": "Jackal"
            },
            {
                "label": "MISC",
                "start": 50,
                "end": 59,
                "text": "Institute"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 114,
                "end": 120,
                "text": "Core's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "However, Darrow's controls are overridden by the proctors saying it would be a suicide mission.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 9,
                "end": 17,
                "text": "Darrow's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "As Aja and the not-so-loyal Tactus walk in from Lorn's estate, they not only meet the Howler's but also see that Darrow obviously knew of the ambush, making it seem like Arcos warned his Student.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 3,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Aja"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 28,
                "end": 34,
                "text": "Tactus"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 48,
                "end": 54,
                "text": "Lorn's"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 86,
                "end": 94,
                "text": "Howler's"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 113,
                "end": 119,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 170,
                "end": 175,
                "text": "Arcos"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Mustang readies for a fight, telling Darrow to pay attention to what he's released into the world.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 7,
                "text": "Mustang"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 37,
                "end": 43,
                "text": "Darrow"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "He has earned their trust.",
        "mentions": []
    },
    {
        "text": "Mustang enters, revealing just how close she has gotten with House Lune.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 7,
                "text": "Mustang"
            },
            {
                "label": "Planet",
                "start": 61,
                "end": 71,
                "text": "House Lune"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "After he wins his match, Sefi scolds him, but he digresses, instead attempting to guilt Sefi for not only taking them in as hostages/wards, but also for leaving Darrow before he left for Venus in Iron Gold.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 25,
                "end": 29,
                "text": "Sefi"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 88,
                "end": 92,
                "text": "Sefi"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 161,
                "end": 167,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "Planet",
                "start": 187,
                "end": 192,
                "text": "Venus"
            },
            {
                "label": "MISC",
                "start": 196,
                "end": 205,
                "text": "Iron Gold"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "He also tells them about how some ships went missing in the Kuiper Belt, and years later one of the Ascommani was seen.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 60,
                "end": 71,
                "text": "Kuiper Belt"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 100,
                "end": 109,
                "text": "Ascommani"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "A hole appears in a the metal bulkhead where she's getting cleaned up, and gravity is lost throughout the ship, slowing them down.",
        "mentions": []
    },
    {
        "text": "Dancer is alive and his face appears and the old Red assures Darrow that his family is safe.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Dancer"
            },
            {
                "label": "Caste",
                "start": 49,
                "end": 52,
                "text": "Red"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 61,
                "end": 67,
                "text": "Darrow"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "He has Thraxa interrogate him.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 7,
                "end": 13,
                "text": "Thraxa"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Darrow announces that the Reaper of Mars is calling for the first Iron Rain in twenty years.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "MISC",
                "start": 26,
                "end": 40,
                "text": "Reaper of Mars"
            },
            {
                "label": "Ritual/Holiday",
                "start": 66,
                "end": 75,
                "text": "Iron Rain"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "The Sovereign is alive and escaped, but badly wounded from the explosion.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Rank",
                "start": 2,
                "end": 11,
                "text": "Sovereign"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Darrow tells them all that he will wait for the Republic and his wife to send aid, and orders that they share their supplies with the civilians, despite the fact that it won't last a week if they do, as per Thraxa's argument.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 48,
                "end": 56,
                "text": "Republic"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 207,
                "end": 215,
                "text": "Thraxa's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Harmony comes in and delivers a speech that's supposed to make the girls feel honored to be chosen.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 7,
                "text": "Harmony"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "In his pain and rage, Darrow agrees to the plan.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 20,
                "end": 26,
                "text": "Darrow"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "When Ephraim detects they are not alone, they start to go back to the ship, but find that Freihild has been killed, by Volsung FÃ¡.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 5,
                "end": 12,
                "text": "Ephraim"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 90,
                "end": 98,
                "text": "Freihild"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 119,
                "end": 129,
                "text": "Volsung FÃ¡"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Virginia realizes then that Lilath is the Syndicate Queen.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 8,
                "text": "Virginia"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 28,
                "end": 34,
                "text": "Lilath"
            },
            {
                "label": "Rank",
                "start": 42,
                "end": 57,
                "text": "Syndicate Queen"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "They bring in Sevro, Pebble, and Clown and before the Abomination.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 14,
                "end": 19,
                "text": "Sevro"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 21,
                "end": 27,
                "text": "Pebble"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 33,
                "end": 38,
                "text": "Clown"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 54,
                "end": 65,
                "text": "Abomination"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Kavax, who is still healing, opts to go for a swim instead of going to the Citadel for the voting as he doesn't like to be there without Niobe.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 5,
                "text": "Kavax"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 75,
                "end": 82,
                "text": "Citadel"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 137,
                "end": 142,
                "text": "Niobe"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "His last opponent, Karnus au Bellona- brother to Julian and Cassius from Darrow's days at the Institute-is left with only one ship.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 19,
                "end": 36,
                "text": "Karnus au Bellona"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 49,
                "end": 55,
                "text": "Julian"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 60,
                "end": 67,
                "text": "Cassius"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 73,
                "end": 81,
                "text": "Darrow's"
            },
            {
                "label": "MISC",
                "start": 94,
                "end": 103,
                "text": "Institute"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Pax and Electra manage to escape Eagle Rest with Ephraim; Pax is flying Snowball, with Ephraim just barely surviving thanks to Electra.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 3,
                "text": "Pax"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 8,
                "end": 15,
                "text": "Electra"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 33,
                "end": 43,
                "text": "Eagle Rest"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 49,
                "end": 56,
                "text": "Ephraim"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 58,
                "end": 61,
                "text": "Pax"
            },
            {
                "label": "Vehicle",
                "start": 72,
                "end": 80,
                "text": "Snowball"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 87,
                "end": 94,
                "text": "Ephraim"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 127,
                "end": 134,
                "text": "Electra"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "And so Darrow sacrifices himself in the name of the greater good for which Eo, his true love and inspiration, laid down her own life.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 3,
                "end": 9,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 71,
                "end": 73,
                "text": "Eo"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Renaming the ship Pax, Darrow tells the Blues on the bridge he will need a new commander for the ship and wants one of them to fill the opening, a position historically held by golds.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Vehicle",
                "start": 18,
                "end": 21,
                "text": "Pax"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 23,
                "end": 29,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "Caste",
                "start": 40,
                "end": 45,
                "text": "Blues"
            },
            {
                "label": "Caste",
                "start": 177,
                "end": 182,
                "text": "golds"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Lysander, who had just been hit and berated by Ajax moments prior for allowing himself to be ward to Cassius, also states his desire to join the Iron Rain, alongside Ajax.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 8,
                "text": "Lysander"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 47,
                "end": 51,
                "text": "Ajax"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 101,
                "end": 108,
                "text": "Cassius"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 166,
                "end": 170,
                "text": "Ajax"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Their interference gives Karnus the win.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 25,
                "end": 31,
                "text": "Karnus"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "In a secret meeting, Glirastes explains why he sided with Darrow and at first is not willing to help Lysander, but when Lysander lies to him about seeing Tyche go down, it convinces Glirastes to side with Lysander.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 21,
                "end": 30,
                "text": "Glirastes"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 58,
                "end": 64,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 101,
                "end": 109,
                "text": "Lysander"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 120,
                "end": 128,
                "text": "Lysander"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 154,
                "end": 159,
                "text": "Tyche"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 182,
                "end": 191,
                "text": "Glirastes"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 205,
                "end": 213,
                "text": "Lysander"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Though Pax's conversation with Holiday is not detailed, it's likely he told her of his deeds with the Alltribe and his sacrifice.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 7,
                "end": 12,
                "text": "Pax's"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 31,
                "end": 38,
                "text": "Holiday"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 102,
                "end": 110,
                "text": "Alltribe"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Darrow asks Harnassus if Glirastes would cross them, but he and Thraxa don't think so.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 12,
                "end": 21,
                "text": "Harnassus"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 25,
                "end": 34,
                "text": "Glirastes"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 64,
                "end": 70,
                "text": "Thraxa"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Lyria is being held prisoner by Victra, even after telling Victra everything she had already told Virginia.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 5,
                "text": "Lyria"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 32,
                "end": 38,
                "text": "Victra"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 59,
                "end": 65,
                "text": "Victra"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 98,
                "end": 106,
                "text": "Virginia"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Mustang briefs the remaining loyalists on what happened, that Augustus was taken by the Rage Knight Fitchner and the Morning Knight Cassius, but only after Nero killed the Hearth Knight.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 7,
                "text": "Mustang"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 62,
                "end": 70,
                "text": "Augustus"
            },
            {
                "label": "Rank",
                "start": 88,
                "end": 99,
                "text": "Rage Knight"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 100,
                "end": 108,
                "text": "Fitchner"
            },
            {
                "label": "Rank",
                "start": 117,
                "end": 131,
                "text": "Morning Knight"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 132,
                "end": 139,
                "text": "Cassius"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 156,
                "end": 160,
                "text": "Nero"
            },
            {
                "label": "Rank",
                "start": 172,
                "end": 185,
                "text": "Hearth Knight"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "After some back and forth, Mustang agrees that the death of her father is the best thing for the society.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 27,
                "end": 34,
                "text": "Mustang"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "He confesses that Darrow is his closest friend and truly a brother.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 18,
                "end": 24,
                "text": "Darrow"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Virginia gives Theodora the order to turn him into a Splinter, Theodora's elite assassins.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 8,
                "text": "Virginia"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 15,
                "end": 23,
                "text": "Theodora"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 53,
                "end": 61,
                "text": "Splinter"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Unable to sleep, Darrow finds Mustang in the mess hall.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 17,
                "end": 23,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 30,
                "end": 37,
                "text": "Mustang"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Volga had sneaked out twelve hours after Ephraim was supposed to return, and was found holding what was left of Ephraim's body.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 40,
                "end": 47,
                "text": "Ephraim"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 111,
                "end": 120,
                "text": "Ephraim's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Though they are successful in rescuing Orion, it's obvious she has endured torture.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 39,
                "end": 44,
                "text": "Orion"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "With the help of Maeve, Lyria disguises herself as a young girl is able to get herself picked up by Picker's boys.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 17,
                "end": 22,
                "text": "Maeve"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 24,
                "end": 29,
                "text": "Lyria"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 100,
                "end": 108,
                "text": "Picker's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "In a last-ditch effort, Darrow attempts to use the pod's Mech Suit, traditionally used for planetary invasions known as Iron Rains, to launch himself into his enemies bridge.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 24,
                "end": 30,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "Technology",
                "start": 57,
                "end": 66,
                "text": "Mech Suit"
            },
            {
                "label": "Ritual/Holiday",
                "start": 120,
                "end": 130,
                "text": "Iron Rains"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Everything is smaller and less severe.",
        "mentions": []
    },
    {
        "text": "Fitchner, all the while, is arguing that Darrow would be more valuable as a prisoner or that they should torture him for information.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 8,
                "text": "Fitchner"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 41,
                "end": 47,
                "text": "Darrow"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "When all the girls are chosen, Lyria starts feeling the drug take effect on her during the ceremony and throughout the celebration.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 31,
                "end": 36,
                "text": "Lyria"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "The Abomination threatens to use the psychospikes on Sevro's mind before erasing it all together.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 4,
                "end": 15,
                "text": "Abomination"
            },
            {
                "label": "Technology",
                "start": 37,
                "end": 49,
                "text": "psychospikes"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 53,
                "end": 60,
                "text": "Sevro's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "One of the girls joining Lyria is Mora, Brea's younger sister, whose nicknamed Lion.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 25,
                "end": 30,
                "text": "Lyria"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 34,
                "end": 38,
                "text": "Mora"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 40,
                "end": 46,
                "text": "Brea's"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 79,
                "end": 83,
                "text": "Lion"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "After being left to die by Tactus, Darrow narrowly makes it to his personal escape pod.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 27,
                "end": 33,
                "text": "Tactus"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 35,
                "end": 41,
                "text": "Darrow"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Niobe is headed to Mars to rendezvous with their house fleets.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 5,
                "text": "Niobe"
            },
            {
                "label": "Planet",
                "start": 19,
                "end": 23,
                "text": "Mars"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Harnassus, Thraxa, and Screwface discuss what to do next.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 9,
                "text": "Harnassus"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 11,
                "end": 17,
                "text": "Thraxa"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 23,
                "end": 32,
                "text": "Screwface"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "But Virginia's main purpose is to get the Optimate Party to convince enough voters to get her a Forum and the power over the defense fleets so she can aid Darrow.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 4,
                "end": 14,
                "text": "Virginia's"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 42,
                "end": 56,
                "text": "Optimate Party"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 155,
                "end": 161,
                "text": "Darrow"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "They are all tortured by the Gorgons and have lost their hair from the radiation off the Ladon.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 29,
                "end": 36,
                "text": "Gorgons"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 89,
                "end": 94,
                "text": "Ladon"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Later that night, Kalindora dies.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 18,
                "end": 27,
                "text": "Kalindora"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Victraâ€™s motherâ€™s forces were also involved in the coup, creating distrust around Victra, but after a short bout and words from Roque about Victraâ€™s loyalty, Darrow reassures everyone that Victra's loyalty is unquestionable.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 8,
                "text": "Victraâ€™s"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 82,
                "end": 88,
                "text": "Victra"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 128,
                "end": 133,
                "text": "Roque"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 140,
                "end": 148,
                "text": "Victraâ€™s"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 158,
                "end": 164,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 189,
                "end": 197,
                "text": "Victra's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "As the celebrations go on through the night, Atalantia and Lysander have sex in her meditation chamber in the Annihilo.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 45,
                "end": 54,
                "text": "Atalantia"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 59,
                "end": 67,
                "text": "Lysander"
            },
            {
                "label": "Vehicle",
                "start": 110,
                "end": 118,
                "text": "Annihilo"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Though the road ahead is fraught with danger and deceit, Darrow must choose to follow Eoâ€™s principles of love and justice to free his people.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 51,
                "end": 57,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 80,
                "end": 84,
                "text": "Eoâ€™s"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "He then announces to the rest of the ship that rather than venting everyone into space, they should join him.",
        "mentions": []
    },
    {
        "text": "As they move through the city, Sevro, possessing the only working pair of grav boots, comes back with news that Ragnar managed to open the gates, kill the Wind Knight, and almost killed Cassius.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 31,
                "end": 36,
                "text": "Sevro"
            },
            {
                "label": "Technology",
                "start": 74,
                "end": 84,
                "text": "grav boots"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 112,
                "end": 118,
                "text": "Ragnar"
            },
            {
                "label": "Rank",
                "start": 155,
                "end": 166,
                "text": "Wind Knight"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 186,
                "end": 193,
                "text": "Cassius"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "They go to one of the houses, where a red, Cormac O'Vadros, lives with his daughter, Brea, and son, Alred.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Caste",
                "start": 38,
                "end": 41,
                "text": "red"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 43,
                "end": 58,
                "text": "Cormac O'Vadros"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 85,
                "end": 89,
                "text": "Brea"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 100,
                "end": 105,
                "text": "Alred"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Sevro says he of course is still loyal to Darrow, but admits not everyone will be.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 5,
                "text": "Sevro"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 42,
                "end": 48,
                "text": "Darrow"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "The plan is for him to detonate a radium bomb at an upcoming gala at which all the Gold leaders across the Society will be, killing nearly every Gold of note.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Caste",
                "start": 83,
                "end": 87,
                "text": "Gold"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 107,
                "end": 114,
                "text": "Society"
            },
            {
                "label": "Caste",
                "start": 145,
                "end": 149,
                "text": "Gold"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "They reach a Citadel wall, but after getting Darrow up, Sevro's grav boots go out.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 13,
                "end": 20,
                "text": "Citadel"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 45,
                "end": 51,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 56,
                "end": 63,
                "text": "Sevro's"
            },
            {
                "label": "Technology",
                "start": 64,
                "end": 74,
                "text": "grav boots"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "And then teaches them how to lie by playing karachi, a card game which is presumably a game of skills and technique, much like poker.",
        "mentions": []
    },
    {
        "text": "While waiting for Freihild, Ephraim goes to get another coat in his ship and stumbles across a field of nightgaze, near where the remains of Alia Snowsparrow's old throne is.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 18,
                "end": 26,
                "text": "Freihild"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 28,
                "end": 35,
                "text": "Ephraim"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 141,
                "end": 159,
                "text": "Alia Snowsparrow's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Rhone is later taken by some of the Rising soldiers, but Cicero and some of his men find them.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 5,
                "text": "Rhone"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 36,
                "end": 42,
                "text": "Rising"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 57,
                "end": 63,
                "text": "Cicero"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "He realizes he can't rely on Virginia or the Republic coming to their aid, knowing that Virginia might be dead.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 29,
                "end": 37,
                "text": "Virginia"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 45,
                "end": 53,
                "text": "Republic"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 88,
                "end": 96,
                "text": "Virginia"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Pytha is there at Lysander's Triumph, and plans to stay with him.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 5,
                "text": "Pytha"
            },
            {
                "label": "Ritual/Holiday",
                "start": 29,
                "end": 36,
                "text": "Triumph"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 18,
                "end": 28,
                "text": "Lysander's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "He's also handed a holodrop that reveals it was Xenophon was the intermediary for FÃ¡, and Ozgard and Amel were framed.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Technology",
                "start": 19,
                "end": 27,
                "text": "holodrop"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 48,
                "end": 56,
                "text": "Xenophon"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 82,
                "end": 84,
                "text": "FÃ¡"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 90,
                "end": 96,
                "text": "Ozgard"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 101,
                "end": 105,
                "text": "Amel"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Unfortunately, Quinn dies, leaving Roque completely broken and Sevro rethinking the glory of war.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 15,
                "end": 20,
                "text": "Quinn"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 35,
                "end": 40,
                "text": "Roque"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 63,
                "end": 68,
                "text": "Sevro"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "She gives a silent apology to Ozgard and Ephraim before she goes into one-on-one combat with FÃ¡.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 30,
                "end": 36,
                "text": "Ozgard"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 41,
                "end": 48,
                "text": "Ephraim"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 93,
                "end": 95,
                "text": "FÃ¡"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Despite Quicksilver's position and prior aid from his company, Virginia denies their proposals and she demands their votes instead.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 8,
                "end": 21,
                "text": "Quicksilver's"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 63,
                "end": 71,
                "text": "Virginia"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "As Ajax prepares his legion, the Iron Leopards, for the battle, he lets them know they are not going to assist Scorpio au Votum to take Tyche as agreed upon by Atalantia, but they are going to take Heliopolis instead, much to Lysander's disappointment.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 3,
                "end": 7,
                "text": "Ajax"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 33,
                "end": 46,
                "text": "Iron Leopards"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 111,
                "end": 127,
                "text": "Scorpio au Votum"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 136,
                "end": 141,
                "text": "Tyche"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 160,
                "end": 169,
                "text": "Atalantia"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 198,
                "end": 208,
                "text": "Heliopolis"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 226,
                "end": 236,
                "text": "Lysander's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "She was completely wiped from all records.",
        "mentions": []
    },
    {
        "text": "They are then brought to one of the mines.",
        "mentions": []
    },
    {
        "text": "He knows that Glirastes has flipped sides and that the EMP will be used against them.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 14,
                "end": 23,
                "text": "Glirastes"
            },
            {
                "label": "Weapon",
                "start": 55,
                "end": 58,
                "text": "EMP"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Ugly Dan, along with the rest of the mine, is not at all how he remembers it.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 8,
                "text": "Ugly Dan"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Smiles stick to Bellona faces and even the Sovereign herself seems pleased with her new Olympic Knight.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 14,
                "end": 21,
                "text": "Bellona"
            },
            {
                "label": "Rank",
                "start": 41,
                "end": 50,
                "text": "Sovereign"
            },
            {
                "label": "Rank",
                "start": 86,
                "end": 100,
                "text": "Olympic Knight"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "During the feast held in Freihild's honor, Valdir voices his disbelief of the Ascomanni and FÃ¡, even challenging Sefi before storming out.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 25,
                "end": 35,
                "text": "Freihild's"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 43,
                "end": 49,
                "text": "Valdir"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 92,
                "end": 94,
                "text": "FÃ¡"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 78,
                "end": 87,
                "text": "Ascomanni"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 113,
                "end": 117,
                "text": "Sefi"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Apollonius au Valii-Rath makes his presence known to Lysander, apparently having followed him for a while.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 24,
                "text": "Apollonius au Valii-Rath"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 53,
                "end": 61,
                "text": "Lysander"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "It shows the readout of the cortical implant in Lyria and states it is impaired.",
        "mentions": []
    },
    {
        "text": "They decide to go to Hildas Station, where the Jackal and Mustang's forces are being kept.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 15,
                "end": 29,
                "text": "Hildas Station"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 41,
                "end": 47,
                "text": "Jackal"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 52,
                "end": 61,
                "text": "Mustang's"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 85,
                "end": 89,
                "text": "Lorn"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Pax also offers his help with the parasite in her.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 3,
                "text": "Pax"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Only seven Golds and five Praetorian Grays survive the days in the desert.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Caste",
                "start": 11,
                "end": 16,
                "text": "Golds"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 26,
                "end": 36,
                "text": "Praetorian"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 37,
                "end": 42,
                "text": "Grays"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "During the ritual, Valdir shows his displeasure and voices his anger, stating that Ephraim's plan will fail.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 19,
                "end": 25,
                "text": "Valdir"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 83,
                "end": 92,
                "text": "Ephraim's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Aja's escape is yet another rift between Darrow and Roque.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 39,
                "end": 45,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 50,
                "end": 55,
                "text": "Roque"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "They inject themselves with the stims they've found, and give Lysander one as well, immediately giving him relief from his burned face.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 62,
                "end": 70,
                "text": "Lysander"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Sevro reveals that Ares contacted him three months prior to arriving in Luna.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 5,
                "text": "Sevro"
            },
            {
                "label": "Rank",
                "start": 19,
                "end": 23,
                "text": "Ares"
            },
            {
                "label": "Planet",
                "start": 72,
                "end": 76,
                "text": "Luna"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "At the Via Triumphia, they're met with Lysander and his men, who've arrived on sunblood horses.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 7,
                "end": 20,
                "text": "Via Triumphia"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 39,
                "end": 47,
                "text": "Lysander"
            },
            {
                "label": "MISC",
                "start": 79,
                "end": 87,
                "text": "sunblood"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Volga makes sure all weapons of theirs are disassembled, and though Cormac is friendly, Lyria stays armed with a pistol.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 5,
                "text": "Volga"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 68,
                "end": 74,
                "text": "Cormac"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 88,
                "end": 93,
                "text": "Lyria"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "As a Red, Darrow grew up working the mines deep beneath the surface of Mars, enduring backbreaking labor while dreaming of the better future he was building for his descendants.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Caste",
                "start": 5,
                "end": 8,
                "text": "Red"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 10,
                "end": 16,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "Planet",
                "start": 71,
                "end": 75,
                "text": "Mars"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "She tells Lyria of what happened in the village and how the Hand had taken many of the young girls there to be childwives, including Brea's younger sister, Mora.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 10,
                "end": 15,
                "text": "Lyria"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 60,
                "end": 64,
                "text": "Hand"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 133,
                "end": 139,
                "text": "Brea's"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 156,
                "end": 160,
                "text": "Mora"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "He alerts all of them, including Alexandar and Rhonna through their cochlear implants, who are visiting with Cato.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 33,
                "end": 42,
                "text": "Alexandar"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 47,
                "end": 53,
                "text": "Rhonna"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 109,
                "end": 113,
                "text": "Cato"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "When asked to join in the Iron Rain they have planned, Diomedes tells Atalantia he cannot join as that is not what he's there for, but Seraphina requests to join in his place, despite her brother's disapproval.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 55,
                "end": 63,
                "text": "Diomedes"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 70,
                "end": 79,
                "text": "Atalantia"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 135,
                "end": 144,
                "text": "Seraphina"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "However, she's still able to manipulate Duncan into showing her where Volga is imprisoned, and later, gets the information about Victra's whereabouts before he dies from the poison she hid in one of her tooth implants.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 40,
                "end": 46,
                "text": "Duncan"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 70,
                "end": 75,
                "text": "Volga"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 129,
                "end": 137,
                "text": "Victra's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Sefi lets Ozgard stay with the Alltribe, but he is to be ignored by all.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 4,
                "text": "Sefi"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 10,
                "end": 16,
                "text": "Ozgard"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 31,
                "end": 39,
                "text": "Alltribe"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "By the time Darrow and the other Howlers get to Lady Beatrice, Alexandar is already dead and Rhonna beaten.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 12,
                "end": 18,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 33,
                "end": 40,
                "text": "Howlers"
            },
            {
                "label": "Rank",
                "start": 48,
                "end": 52,
                "text": "Lady"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 53,
                "end": 61,
                "text": "Beatrice"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 63,
                "end": 72,
                "text": "Alexandar"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 93,
                "end": 99,
                "text": "Rhonna"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Lysander au Lune, the heir in exile, has returned to the Core.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 16,
                "text": "Lysander au Lune"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 57,
                "end": 61,
                "text": "Core"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Rhonna brings him an enemy in Fulminata uniform, but when they reveal his face, he knows it's Screwface, who was carved to go undercover in Atalantia's army.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Rhonna"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 30,
                "end": 39,
                "text": "Fulminata"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 94,
                "end": 103,
                "text": "Screwface"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 140,
                "end": 151,
                "text": "Atalantia's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Screwface and Thraxa also make it back.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 9,
                "text": "Screwface"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 14,
                "end": 20,
                "text": "Thraxa"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "She offers a position by her side, but Darrow rejects.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 39,
                "end": 45,
                "text": "Darrow"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "He uses the Mind's Eye kill them, including Seneca, and is injured even more.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "MISC",
                "start": 12,
                "end": 22,
                "text": "Mind's Eye"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 44,
                "end": 50,
                "text": "Seneca"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "They constantly beat and humiliate him.",
        "mentions": []
    },
    {
        "text": "Xenophon stats that Atlas infiltrated the Ascomanni by having his best Gorgon, Volsung FÃ¡, infiltrate the group.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 8,
                "text": "Xenophon"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 20,
                "end": 25,
                "text": "Atlas"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 42,
                "end": 51,
                "text": "Ascomanni"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 71,
                "end": 77,
                "text": "Gorgon"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 79,
                "end": 89,
                "text": "Volsung FÃ¡"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "As they duel, Darrow bests Cassius easily, severing his arm, which forces the Sovereignâ€™s hand to try and stop Darrow from killing her newest Olympic Knight.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 12,
                "end": 18,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 25,
                "end": 32,
                "text": "Cassius"
            },
            {
                "label": "Rank",
                "start": 76,
                "end": 87,
                "text": "Sovereignâ€™s"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 109,
                "end": 115,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
