[
    {
        "text": "When they finally arrive at Tyche, Darrow realizes that Orion defied his order to keep the Storm God level to a minimum and has already destroyed much of the city and killed millions, Golds and civilians alike.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "LOC",
                "start": 28,
                "end": 33,
                "text": "Tyche"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 35,
                "end": 41,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 56,
                "end": 61,
                "text": "Orion"
            },
            {
                "label": "TECH",
                "start": 91,
                "end": 100,
                "text": "Storm God"
            },
            {
                "label": "CASTE",
                "start": 184,
                "end": 189,
                "text": "Golds"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Darrow, Sevro, and several others from the Seventh Legion return home to Luna from a triumphant, weary year-long mission on Mercury that ended with an Iron Rain that liberated the Planet.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 8,
                "end": 13,
                "text": "Sevro"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 43,
                "end": 57,
                "text": "Seventh Legion"
            },
            {
                "label": "PLANET",
                "start": 73,
                "end": 77,
                "text": "Luna"
            },
            {
                "label": "PLANET",
                "start": 124,
                "end": 131,
                "text": "Mercury"
            },
            {
                "label": "RITUAL",
                "start": 151,
                "end": 160,
                "text": "Iron Rain"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "In a fearsome new world where Obsidian pirates roam the Belt, famine and genocide ravage Mars, and crime lords terrorize Luna, itâ€™s time for Darrow and a cast of new characters from across the solar system to face down the chaos that revolution has unleashed.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "CASTE",
                "start": 30,
                "end": 38,
                "text": "Obsidian"
            },
            {
                "label": "LOC",
                "start": 56,
                "end": 60,
                "text": "Belt"
            },
            {
                "label": "PLANET",
                "start": 89,
                "end": 93,
                "text": "Mars"
            },
            {
                "label": "PLANET",
                "start": 121,
                "end": 125,
                "text": "Luna"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 141,
                "end": 147,
                "text": "Darrow"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Lysander finds that Thraxa, Harnassus, and the core of Howlers escaped alongside Darrow on the Archimedes, while those who were left behind are thrown into manual labor to rebuild the city after The Long Night.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 8,
                "text": "Lysander"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 20,
                "end": 26,
                "text": "Thraxa"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 28,
                "end": 37,
                "text": "Harnassus"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 55,
                "end": 62,
                "text": "Howlers"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 81,
                "end": 87,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "VEHICLE",
                "start": 95,
                "end": 105,
                "text": "Archimedes"
            },
            {
                "label": "EVENT",
                "start": 199,
                "end": 209,
                "text": "Long Night"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Lyria and Freckles find Harmony's room, where there are two razors, a Gold pulseArmor breastplate, a map, and a communications console.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 5,
                "text": "Lyria"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 10,
                "end": 18,
                "text": "Freckles"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 24,
                "end": 33,
                "text": "Harmony's"
            },
            {
                "label": "WEAPON",
                "start": 60,
                "end": 66,
                "text": "razors"
            },
            {
                "label": "CASTE",
                "start": 70,
                "end": 74,
                "text": "Gold"
            },
            {
                "label": "TECH",
                "start": 75,
                "end": 85,
                "text": "pulseArmor"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "To add insult to injury, Darrow is then informed by Nero au Augustus and his chief politico Pliny that due to the embarrassment of losing to a Bellona, they will be removing him from his position as lancer.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 25,
                "end": 31,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 52,
                "end": 68,
                "text": "Nero au Augustus"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 92,
                "end": 97,
                "text": "Pliny"
            },
            {
                "label": "PROFESSION",
                "start": 77,
                "end": 91,
                "text": "chief politico"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 143,
                "end": 150,
                "text": "Bellona"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 199,
                "end": 205,
                "text": "lancer"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "As House Augustus tries to make their escape, they come across the former Mars proctor from the Institute, Fitchner au Barca, who is now holds Arcos' old position, the Rage Knight.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 3,
                "end": 17,
                "text": "House Augustus"
            },
            {
                "label": "MISC",
                "start": 96,
                "end": 105,
                "text": "Institute"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 107,
                "end": 124,
                "text": "Fitchner au Barca"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 143,
                "end": 148,
                "text": "Arcos"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 168,
                "end": 179,
                "text": "Rage Knight"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 74,
                "end": 78,
                "text": "Mars"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "The former Red finds himself surrounded by Karnus, Aja, Fitchner, and the Sovereign surrounded by her Praetorians.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "CASTE",
                "start": 11,
                "end": 14,
                "text": "Red"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 43,
                "end": 49,
                "text": "Karnus"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 51,
                "end": 54,
                "text": "Aja"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 56,
                "end": 64,
                "text": "Fitchner"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 74,
                "end": 83,
                "text": "Sovereign"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 102,
                "end": 113,
                "text": "Praetorians"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "The Julii military and aid ships did not arrive on Olympia until three days after Volsung FÃ¡ and the Obsidians had left.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 4,
                "end": 9,
                "text": "Julii"
            },
            {
                "label": "LOC",
                "start": 51,
                "end": 58,
                "text": "Olympia"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 82,
                "end": 92,
                "text": "Volsung FÃ¡"
            },
            {
                "label": "CASTE",
                "start": 101,
                "end": 110,
                "text": "Obsidians"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Having now pieced together The Sovereigns plan, Darrow takes the opportunity to ask if Octavia had planned for House Bellona to kill the ArchGovernor Augustus and everyone at his table during the Sixth Course of dinner, she denies it, but the Oracle bites, revealing her lie.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 31,
                "end": 41,
                "text": "Sovereigns"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 48,
                "end": 54,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 87,
                "end": 94,
                "text": "Octavia"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 111,
                "end": 124,
                "text": "House Bellona"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 137,
                "end": 149,
                "text": "ArchGovernor"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 150,
                "end": 158,
                "text": "Augustus"
            },
            {
                "label": "MISC",
                "start": 243,
                "end": 249,
                "text": "Oracle"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "On the day of the voting, Sevro leaves for Earth with fifty thousand of Virginia's men and Darrow's Seventh Legion, where they believe the Syndicate Queen to be, to kill her.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 26,
                "end": 31,
                "text": "Sevro"
            },
            {
                "label": "PLANET",
                "start": 43,
                "end": 48,
                "text": "Earth"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 72,
                "end": 82,
                "text": "Virginia's"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 91,
                "end": 99,
                "text": "Darrow's"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 100,
                "end": 114,
                "text": "Seventh Legion"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 139,
                "end": 154,
                "text": "Syndicate Queen"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Out of desperation, he and Victra secretly meet with Adrius au Augustus, commonly known as \"The Jackal,\" in the Lost City on Luna.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 27,
                "end": 33,
                "text": "Victra"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 53,
                "end": 71,
                "text": "Adrius au Augustus"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 96,
                "end": 102,
                "text": "Jackal"
            },
            {
                "label": "LOC",
                "start": 112,
                "end": 121,
                "text": "Lost City"
            },
            {
                "label": "PLANET",
                "start": 125,
                "end": 129,
                "text": "Luna"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "The rest of his old retinue has been scattered across the solar system, notably Sevro and the Howlers who have been sent to far orbit, and Mustang who has taken up politics on Luna.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 80,
                "end": 85,
                "text": "Sevro"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 94,
                "end": 101,
                "text": "Howlers"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 139,
                "end": 146,
                "text": "Mustang"
            },
            {
                "label": "PLANET",
                "start": 176,
                "end": 180,
                "text": "Luna"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "That night, Cicero suggests killing the Grays since he's sure they'll run out of water before they reach the closest city, Erebos, but Lysander refuses.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 12,
                "end": 18,
                "text": "Cicero"
            },
            {
                "label": "CASTE",
                "start": 40,
                "end": 45,
                "text": "Grays"
            },
            {
                "label": "LOC",
                "start": 123,
                "end": 129,
                "text": "Erebos"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 135,
                "end": 143,
                "text": "Lysander"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "On his way back to Eagle Rest from a walk around the city, Ephraim sees on someone's datapad that the Pandora has been attacked.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "LOC",
                "start": 19,
                "end": 29,
                "text": "Eagle Rest"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 59,
                "end": 66,
                "text": "Ephraim"
            },
            {
                "label": "VEHICLE",
                "start": 102,
                "end": 109,
                "text": "Pandora"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Darrow sends Ragnar and the other Obsidians, all now Razor armed, to attack the back of the wall and open the gates for the outside forces.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 13,
                "end": 19,
                "text": "Ragnar"
            },
            {
                "label": "CASTE",
                "start": 34,
                "end": 43,
                "text": "Obsidians"
            },
            {
                "label": "WEAPON",
                "start": 53,
                "end": 58,
                "text": "Razor"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "A decade-long peace still exists between the Republic and the Golds of the Rim worlds, but something stirs in the darkness out beyond the asteroid belt.[2]",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 45,
                "end": 53,
                "text": "Republic"
            },
            {
                "label": "CASTE",
                "start": 62,
                "end": 67,
                "text": "Golds"
            },
            {
                "label": "LOC",
                "start": 75,
                "end": 78,
                "text": "Rim"
            },
            {
                "label": "LOC",
                "start": 138,
                "end": 151,
                "text": "asteroid belt"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "The Jackal has been expanding his power since the Institute and is now in control of a sizeable percentage of the Core's media networks.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 4,
                "end": 10,
                "text": "Jackal"
            },
            {
                "label": "MISC",
                "start": 50,
                "end": 59,
                "text": "Institute"
            },
            {
                "label": "LOC",
                "start": 114,
                "end": 120,
                "text": "Core's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "After he wins his match, Sefi scolds him, but he digresses, instead attempting to guilt Sefi for not only taking them in as hostages/wards, but also for leaving Darrow before he left for Venus in Iron Gold.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 25,
                "end": 29,
                "text": "Sefi"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 88,
                "end": 92,
                "text": "Sefi"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 161,
                "end": 167,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "PLANET",
                "start": 187,
                "end": 192,
                "text": "Venus"
            },
            {
                "label": "MISC",
                "start": 196,
                "end": 205,
                "text": "Iron Gold"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Darrow announces that the Reaper of Mars is calling for the first Iron Rain in twenty years.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "MISC",
                "start": 26,
                "end": 40,
                "text": "Reaper of Mars"
            },
            {
                "label": "RITUAL",
                "start": 66,
                "end": 75,
                "text": "Iron Rain"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Pax and Electra manage to escape Eagle Rest with Ephraim; Pax is flying Snowball, with Ephraim just barely surviving thanks to Electra.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 3,
                "text": "Pax"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 8,
                "end": 15,
                "text": "Electra"
            },
            {
                "label": "LOC",
                "start": 33,
                "end": 43,
                "text": "Eagle Rest"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 49,
                "end": 56,
                "text": "Ephraim"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 58,
                "end": 61,
                "text": "Pax"
            },
            {
                "label": "VEHICLE",
                "start": 72,
                "end": 80,
                "text": "Snowball"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 87,
                "end": 94,
                "text": "Ephraim"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 127,
                "end": 134,
                "text": "Electra"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Renaming the ship Pax, Darrow tells the Blues on the bridge he will need a new commander for the ship and wants one of them to fill the opening, a position historically held by golds.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "VEHICLE",
                "start": 18,
                "end": 21,
                "text": "Pax"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 23,
                "end": 29,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "CASTE",
                "start": 40,
                "end": 45,
                "text": "Blues"
            },
            {
                "label": "CASTE",
                "start": 177,
                "end": 182,
                "text": "golds"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "In a last-ditch effort, Darrow attempts to use the pod's Mech Suit, traditionally used for planetary invasions known as Iron Rains, to launch himself into his enemies bridge.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 24,
                "end": 30,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "TECH",
                "start": 57,
                "end": 66,
                "text": "Mech Suit"
            },
            {
                "label": "RITUAL",
                "start": 120,
                "end": 130,
                "text": "Iron Rains"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "As they move through the city, Sevro, possessing the only working pair of grav boots, comes back with news that Ragnar managed to open the gates, kill the Wind Knight, and almost killed Cassius.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 31,
                "end": 36,
                "text": "Sevro"
            },
            {
                "label": "TECH",
                "start": 74,
                "end": 84,
                "text": "grav boots"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 112,
                "end": 118,
                "text": "Ragnar"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 155,
                "end": 166,
                "text": "Wind Knight"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 186,
                "end": 193,
                "text": "Cassius"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "They reach a Citadel wall, but after getting Darrow up, Sevro's grav boots go out.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "LOC",
                "start": 13,
                "end": 20,
                "text": "Citadel"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 45,
                "end": 51,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 56,
                "end": 63,
                "text": "Sevro's"
            },
            {
                "label": "TECH",
                "start": 64,
                "end": 74,
                "text": "grav boots"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "As Ajax prepares his legion, the Iron Leopards, for the battle, he lets them know they are not going to assist Scorpio au Votum to take Tyche as agreed upon by Atalantia, but they are going to take Heliopolis instead, much to Lysander's disappointment.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 3,
                "end": 7,
                "text": "Ajax"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 33,
                "end": 46,
                "text": "Iron Leopards"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 111,
                "end": 127,
                "text": "Scorpio au Votum"
            },
            {
                "label": "LOC",
                "start": 136,
                "end": 141,
                "text": "Tyche"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 160,
                "end": 169,
                "text": "Atalantia"
            },
            {
                "label": "LOC",
                "start": 198,
                "end": 208,
                "text": "Heliopolis"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 226,
                "end": 236,
                "text": "Lysander's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Only seven Golds and five Praetorian Grays survive the days in the desert.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "CASTE",
                "start": 11,
                "end": 16,
                "text": "Golds"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 26,
                "end": 36,
                "text": "Praetorian"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 37,
                "end": 42,
                "text": "Grays"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Sevro reveals that Ares contacted him three months prior to arriving in Luna.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 5,
                "text": "Sevro"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 19,
                "end": 23,
                "text": "Ares"
            },
            {
                "label": "PLANET",
                "start": 72,
                "end": 76,
                "text": "Luna"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "At the Via Triumphia, they're met with Lysander and his men, who've arrived on sunblood horses.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "LOC",
                "start": 7,
                "end": 20,
                "text": "Via Triumphia"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 39,
                "end": 47,
                "text": "Lysander"
            },
            {
                "label": "MISC",
                "start": 79,
                "end": 87,
                "text": "sunblood"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "As a Red, Darrow grew up working the mines deep beneath the surface of Mars, enduring backbreaking labor while dreaming of the better future he was building for his descendants.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "CASTE",
                "start": 5,
                "end": 8,
                "text": "Red"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 10,
                "end": 16,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "PLANET",
                "start": 71,
                "end": 75,
                "text": "Mars"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "By the time Darrow and the other Howlers get to Lady Beatrice, Alexandar is already dead and Rhonna beaten.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 12,
                "end": 18,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 33,
                "end": 40,
                "text": "Howlers"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 48,
                "end": 52,
                "text": "Lady"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 53,
                "end": 61,
                "text": "Beatrice"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 63,
                "end": 72,
                "text": "Alexandar"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 93,
                "end": 99,
                "text": "Rhonna"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Sefi then tells Ephraim that she plans on taking the Cimmeria mines and needs the Skuggi to be ready.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 4,
                "text": "Sefi"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 16,
                "end": 23,
                "text": "Ephraim"
            },
            {
                "label": "LOC",
                "start": 53,
                "end": 61,
                "text": "Cimmeria"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 82,
                "end": 88,
                "text": "Skuggi"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Despite Plinyâ€™s warning of escalating the war, Darrow's plan of capturing Ganymede's ships and kidnapping the students of the institute is agreed upon by the council.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 8,
                "end": 15,
                "text": "Plinyâ€™s"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 47,
                "end": 55,
                "text": "Darrow's"
            },
            {
                "label": "MISC",
                "start": 126,
                "end": 135,
                "text": "institute"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 74,
                "end": 84,
                "text": "Ganymede's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "He meets Dago of Gamma, the infamous Helldiver from a rival tribe of his.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 9,
                "end": 13,
                "text": "Dago"
            },
            {
                "label": "PROFESSION",
                "start": 37,
                "end": 46,
                "text": "Helldiver"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 17,
                "end": 22,
                "text": "Gamma"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Sefi then tells them that Virginia was killed in the coup, as well as the archGovernor of Mars, and that Sevro has been captured on Earth.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 4,
                "text": "Sefi"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 26,
                "end": 34,
                "text": "Virginia"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 74,
                "end": 86,
                "text": "archGovernor"
            },
            {
                "label": "PLANET",
                "start": 90,
                "end": 94,
                "text": "Mars"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 105,
                "end": 110,
                "text": "Sevro"
            },
            {
                "label": "PLANET",
                "start": 132,
                "end": 137,
                "text": "Earth"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "When the Storm God is activated, Darrow's army intercepts one of the enemy's divisions and are able to take down several legions, as well as Primus Scorpio au Votum.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "TECH",
                "start": 9,
                "end": 18,
                "text": "Storm God"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 33,
                "end": 41,
                "text": "Darrow's"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 141,
                "end": 147,
                "text": "Primus"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 148,
                "end": 164,
                "text": "Scorpio au Votum"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "They track the House Golds, including Nero, Roque and The Jackal, to a swamp where they are rapidly running out of air.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 15,
                "end": 20,
                "text": "House"
            },
            {
                "label": "CASTE",
                "start": 21,
                "end": 26,
                "text": "Golds"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 38,
                "end": 42,
                "text": "Nero"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 44,
                "end": 49,
                "text": "Roque"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 58,
                "end": 64,
                "text": "Jackal"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Now, outlawed by the very Republic he founded, he wages a rogue war on Mercury in hope that he can still salvage the dream of Eo.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 26,
                "end": 34,
                "text": "Republic"
            },
            {
                "label": "PLANET",
                "start": 71,
                "end": 78,
                "text": "Mercury"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 126,
                "end": 128,
                "text": "Eo"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "With Ragnar cleaning up the last of on-board resistance and Mustang & Co. safely on board, they are able to use the immense power of their new starship to fight off the rest of the Sovereigns fleet before escaping past the Rubicon Beacons.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 5,
                "end": 11,
                "text": "Ragnar"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 60,
                "end": 67,
                "text": "Mustang"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 181,
                "end": 191,
                "text": "Sovereigns"
            },
            {
                "label": "TECH",
                "start": 223,
                "end": 238,
                "text": "Rubicon Beacons"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "After he meets alone with Atalantia, she, along with Ajax and Kalindora, as well as the Primuses of House Carthii, House Votum, and House Falthe via hologram.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 26,
                "end": 35,
                "text": "Atalantia"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 53,
                "end": 57,
                "text": "Ajax"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 62,
                "end": 71,
                "text": "Kalindora"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 88,
                "end": 96,
                "text": "Primuses"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 100,
                "end": 113,
                "text": "House Carthii"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 115,
                "end": 126,
                "text": "House Votum"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 132,
                "end": 144,
                "text": "House Falthe"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "It has been over two years since he graduated from the Institute and took a position as lancer for House Augustus.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "MISC",
                "start": 55,
                "end": 64,
                "text": "Institute"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 88,
                "end": 94,
                "text": "lancer"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 99,
                "end": 113,
                "text": "House Augustus"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "With this power, he plans to unseat the Sovereign and destroy the Sons of Ares, using the immensely popular Darrow as a sort of figurehead TV-hero to gather support.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 40,
                "end": 49,
                "text": "Sovereign"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 66,
                "end": 78,
                "text": "Sons of Ares"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 108,
                "end": 114,
                "text": "Darrow"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "After he faces off against Lysander on sunbloods, he makes his way to the Mound of Votum, where all the other survivors have rendezvoused.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 27,
                "end": 35,
                "text": "Lysander"
            },
            {
                "label": "MISC",
                "start": 39,
                "end": 48,
                "text": "sunbloods"
            },
            {
                "label": "LOC",
                "start": 74,
                "end": 88,
                "text": "Mound of Votum"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Pax gives him Trigg's ring, and a disc from Victra, a pass to get past the Republic patrols and off Mars, as a debt was owed to Trigg for saving her life from the Jackal.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 3,
                "text": "Pax"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 14,
                "end": 21,
                "text": "Trigg's"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 44,
                "end": 50,
                "text": "Victra"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 75,
                "end": 83,
                "text": "Republic"
            },
            {
                "label": "PLANET",
                "start": 100,
                "end": 104,
                "text": "Mars"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 128,
                "end": 133,
                "text": "Trigg"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 163,
                "end": 169,
                "text": "Jackal"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "He's greeted by an Obsidian shaman named Ozgard who tells him that they killed the Syndicate men after them.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "CASTE",
                "start": 19,
                "end": 27,
                "text": "Obsidian"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 41,
                "end": 47,
                "text": "Ozgard"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 83,
                "end": 92,
                "text": "Syndicate"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "She gets news that Sevro has killed the Duke of Heads, the chief assassin of the Syndicate, as Sevro has been on a killing spree on orders of his wife, Victra, due to their kidnapped daughter, Electra.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 19,
                "end": 24,
                "text": "Sevro"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 40,
                "end": 53,
                "text": "Duke of Heads"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 81,
                "end": 90,
                "text": "Syndicate"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 95,
                "end": 100,
                "text": "Sevro"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 152,
                "end": 158,
                "text": "Victra"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 193,
                "end": 200,
                "text": "Electra"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "The Reaper of House Mars now trains in the Academy, a prestigious school not unlike the Institute, that focuses on space based warfare and planetary tactics.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 4,
                "end": 10,
                "text": "Reaper"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 14,
                "end": 24,
                "text": "House Mars"
            },
            {
                "label": "MISC",
                "start": 43,
                "end": 50,
                "text": "Academy"
            },
            {
                "label": "MISC",
                "start": 88,
                "end": 97,
                "text": "Institute"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Around them, Lysander has the giant statues of Silenius au Lune and forty more Sovereign statues are placed in a giant circle, all pointing toward Mars.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 13,
                "end": 21,
                "text": "Lysander"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 47,
                "end": 63,
                "text": "Silenius au Lune"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 79,
                "end": 88,
                "text": "Sovereign"
            },
            {
                "label": "PLANET",
                "start": 147,
                "end": 151,
                "text": "Mars"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "The Battle of the Ladon is over, but all the major cities of Helios are now lost and millions of Darrow's men are either dead or missing, along with millions of the citizens of Heliopolis.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "EVENT",
                "start": 4,
                "end": 23,
                "text": "Battle of the Ladon"
            },
            {
                "label": "LOC",
                "start": 61,
                "end": 67,
                "text": "Helios"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 97,
                "end": 105,
                "text": "Darrow's"
            },
            {
                "label": "LOC",
                "start": 177,
                "end": 187,
                "text": "Heliopolis"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "On the ship, they find that the Obsidians living there had come from Mercury, when Cadus Harnassus had released half the fleet back to Luna.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "CASTE",
                "start": 32,
                "end": 41,
                "text": "Obsidians"
            },
            {
                "label": "PLANET",
                "start": 69,
                "end": 76,
                "text": "Mercury"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 83,
                "end": 98,
                "text": "Cadus Harnassus"
            },
            {
                "label": "PLANET",
                "start": 135,
                "end": 139,
                "text": "Luna"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "They meet an Obsidian, a Stained, who introduces himself to them as Ragnar Volarus after he kills four Golds and six Obsidians by himself.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "CASTE",
                "start": 13,
                "end": 21,
                "text": "Obsidian"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 25,
                "end": 32,
                "text": "Stained"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 68,
                "end": 82,
                "text": "Ragnar Volarus"
            },
            {
                "label": "CASTE",
                "start": 103,
                "end": 108,
                "text": "Golds"
            },
            {
                "label": "CASTE",
                "start": 117,
                "end": 126,
                "text": "Obsidians"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "On their way there, Pax tells them of the theory of a group of Obsidians who escaped the genocide and cultural reengineering of their people - the Ascomanni, and how there might be a central force who leads them named Volsung the Taker.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 20,
                "end": 23,
                "text": "Pax"
            },
            {
                "label": "CASTE",
                "start": 63,
                "end": 72,
                "text": "Obsidians"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 147,
                "end": 156,
                "text": "Ascomanni"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 218,
                "end": 235,
                "text": "Volsung the Taker"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "After helping the rest of survivors, the group realizes their team of nearly 3 dozen is reduced to Ragnar, a few obsidian, Darrow, and a handful of Howlers, all without armor.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 99,
                "end": 105,
                "text": "Ragnar"
            },
            {
                "label": "CASTE",
                "start": 113,
                "end": 121,
                "text": "obsidian"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 123,
                "end": 129,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 148,
                "end": 155,
                "text": "Howlers"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Fitchner tells of how he became Ares after Sevro's mom, a Red, was killed after giving birth to Sevro.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 8,
                "text": "Fitchner"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 32,
                "end": 36,
                "text": "Ares"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 43,
                "end": 50,
                "text": "Sevro's"
            },
            {
                "label": "CASTE",
                "start": 58,
                "end": 61,
                "text": "Red"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 96,
                "end": 101,
                "text": "Sevro"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "At Darrowâ€™s Triumph, where the Iron Rain is to be memorialized, Nero au Augustus tells Darrow he will adopt him and make him Heir to house Augustus, all The Jackals idea he says.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 3,
                "end": 11,
                "text": "Darrowâ€™s"
            },
            {
                "label": "RITUAL",
                "start": 12,
                "end": 19,
                "text": "Triumph"
            },
            {
                "label": "RITUAL",
                "start": 31,
                "end": 40,
                "text": "Iron Rain"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 64,
                "end": 80,
                "text": "Nero au Augustus"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 87,
                "end": 93,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 133,
                "end": 147,
                "text": "house Augustus"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 157,
                "end": 164,
                "text": "Jackals"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "He leads the charge riding the largest horse, named Blood of Empire, and blows the Horn of Helios, given to him by Glirastes, as they make their way out of the Hippodrome.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 52,
                "end": 67,
                "text": "Blood of Empire"
            },
            {
                "label": "MISC",
                "start": 83,
                "end": 97,
                "text": "Horn of Helios"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 115,
                "end": 124,
                "text": "Glirastes"
            },
            {
                "label": "LOC",
                "start": 160,
                "end": 170,
                "text": "Hippodrome"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "After Ephraim is seen by the Julii's medici, he and Volga tell each other's stories, but he doesn't tell her about her parentage.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 6,
                "end": 13,
                "text": "Ephraim"
            },
            {
                "label": "PROFESSION",
                "start": 37,
                "end": 43,
                "text": "medici"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 29,
                "end": 36,
                "text": "Julii's"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 52,
                "end": 57,
                "text": "Volga"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "However, Augustus decides that while he will attack Ganymede himself, and his Children will attack the institute, Darrow will try to rally the old Rage Knight Lorn au Arcos to their cause.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 7,
                "end": 15,
                "text": "Augustus"
            },
            {
                "label": "PLANET",
                "start": 50,
                "end": 58,
                "text": "Ganymede"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 112,
                "end": 118,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 145,
                "end": 156,
                "text": "Rage Knight"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 157,
                "end": 170,
                "text": "Lorn au Arcos"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Darrow a whisperGem to watch on his own, revealing a message from a still masked Ares, saying that he was betrayed by Harmony, and that Darrow was right not to use the radium bomb at the gala, and is proud of him and urges him to carry on.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "TECH",
                "start": 9,
                "end": 19,
                "text": "whisperGem"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 81,
                "end": 85,
                "text": "Ares"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 118,
                "end": 125,
                "text": "Harmony"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 136,
                "end": 142,
                "text": "Darrow"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Pax then rushes tells them that Earth has fallen to both the Rim and the Society Remnant, united.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 3,
                "text": "Pax"
            },
            {
                "label": "PLANET",
                "start": 32,
                "end": 37,
                "text": "Earth"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 61,
                "end": 64,
                "text": "Rim"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 73,
                "end": 80,
                "text": "Society"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "There is a sliver of hope however, as Mustang wasn't at the Triumph, the Telemanuses were in Orbit, and Sevro, the Howlers, and Ragnar were not found.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 34,
                "end": 41,
                "text": "Mustang"
            },
            {
                "label": "RITUAL",
                "start": 56,
                "end": 63,
                "text": "Triumph"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 69,
                "end": 80,
                "text": "Telemanuses"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 100,
                "end": 105,
                "text": "Sevro"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 111,
                "end": 118,
                "text": "Howlers"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 124,
                "end": 130,
                "text": "Ragnar"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "After beating him badly, Karnus tells him that his actions against house Bellona will not go unanswered - his Mother wants Darrow's heart.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 25,
                "end": 31,
                "text": "Karnus"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 67,
                "end": 80,
                "text": "house Bellona"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 123,
                "end": 131,
                "text": "Darrow's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Exeter and Glirastes' remaining lowColor staff pledge fealty to Lysander.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Exeter"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 11,
                "end": 20,
                "text": "Glirastes"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 32,
                "end": 40,
                "text": "lowColor"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 64,
                "end": 72,
                "text": "Lysander"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Returning to the Gala, Darrow marches straight to the Bellona table, jumps on top and walks through dinner plates to where Cassius sits.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 23,
                "end": 29,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 54,
                "end": 61,
                "text": "Bellona"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 123,
                "end": 130,
                "text": "Cassius"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Darrow admits he is a red and Sevro says that he was shown the carving when he met with Dancer.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "CASTE",
                "start": 22,
                "end": 25,
                "text": "red"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 30,
                "end": 35,
                "text": "Sevro"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 88,
                "end": 94,
                "text": "Dancer"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Fig, the unusual Brown that took Lyria from Virginia's home escorts her out of the room one day, stating that Ephraim has arranged for her and Volga's release.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 3,
                "text": "Fig"
            },
            {
                "label": "CASTE",
                "start": 17,
                "end": 22,
                "text": "Brown"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 33,
                "end": 38,
                "text": "Lyria"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 44,
                "end": 54,
                "text": "Virginia's"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 110,
                "end": 117,
                "text": "Ephraim"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 143,
                "end": 150,
                "text": "Volga's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "They don't go back to the Citadel, but go in search for Victra.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "LOC",
                "start": 26,
                "end": 33,
                "text": "Citadel"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 56,
                "end": 62,
                "text": "Victra"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Darrow also sees Cassius, who has been made the Morning Knight - one of the Soveriegns' Olympic Knights.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 17,
                "end": 24,
                "text": "Cassius"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 48,
                "end": 62,
                "text": "Morning Knight"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 76,
                "end": 86,
                "text": "Soveriegns"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 88,
                "end": 103,
                "text": "Olympic Knights"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "She plans on becoming the Sovereign, and plans to kill Lysander for it.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 26,
                "end": 35,
                "text": "Sovereign"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 55,
                "end": 63,
                "text": "Lysander"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Roque was able to capture more than eighty percent of the Bellona fleet, making his own larger than Darrow's.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 56,
                "end": 63,
                "text": "Bellona"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 98,
                "end": 106,
                "text": "Darrow's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Publius and the Vox Populi shout tyranny and it becomes a coup, with many people and senators killed.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 7,
                "text": "Publius"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 16,
                "end": 26,
                "text": "Vox Populi"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Sefi at first denies him as her father, but as he continues to speak and reveal memories, as well as a broken amulet of a griffin, the Alltribe, especially the males, slowly start being convinced.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 4,
                "text": "Sefi"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 135,
                "end": 143,
                "text": "Alltribe"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Once they land on the ship, the Love Knight, Kalindora au San, who Lysander thought dead, and Ajax meet them skeptically.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 32,
                "end": 43,
                "text": "Love Knight"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 45,
                "end": 61,
                "text": "Kalindora au San"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 67,
                "end": 75,
                "text": "Lysander"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 94,
                "end": 98,
                "text": "Ajax"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "During the cleanup of the beach, Darrow gave a Razor to Ragnar.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 33,
                "end": 39,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "WEAPON",
                "start": 47,
                "end": 52,
                "text": "Razor"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 56,
                "end": 62,
                "text": "Ragnar"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "With their only protection now gone, and time running out for everyone, Darrow again his failed stunt from he Acadamy.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 72,
                "end": 78,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "MISC",
                "start": 110,
                "end": 117,
                "text": "Acadamy"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "However, he and those with him, including Thraxa au Telemanus, Alexandar au Arcos, Colloway xe Char, Tongueless, and his niece Rhonna, attempt a rescue of one of his most loyal, Orion xe Aquarii, from the ship the Blood Medusa.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 42,
                "end": 61,
                "text": "Thraxa au Telemanus"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 63,
                "end": 81,
                "text": "Alexandar au Arcos"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 83,
                "end": 99,
                "text": "Colloway xe Char"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 101,
                "end": 111,
                "text": "Tongueless"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 127,
                "end": 133,
                "text": "Rhonna"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 178,
                "end": 194,
                "text": "Orion xe Aquarii"
            },
            {
                "label": "VEHICLE",
                "start": 214,
                "end": 226,
                "text": "Blood Medusa"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Virginia is brought to a banquet for the jackals, seated next to the Abomination.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 8,
                "text": "Virginia"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 41,
                "end": 48,
                "text": "jackals"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 69,
                "end": 80,
                "text": "Abomination"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Given only a few days notice rather than the traditional months, the move both destroys any power and clout Darrow may have held and removes all the protections afforded to him by House Augustus.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 108,
                "end": 114,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 180,
                "end": 194,
                "text": "House Augustus"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "He tells them he is Cato au Vetruvius, and Alexandar introduces the rest of them as the Knights of Elysium - Drusilla, Ignacius, Crastus, and Hadrian.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 20,
                "end": 37,
                "text": "Cato au Vetruvius"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 43,
                "end": 52,
                "text": "Alexandar"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 109,
                "end": 117,
                "text": "Drusilla"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 119,
                "end": 127,
                "text": "Ignacius"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 129,
                "end": 136,
                "text": "Crastus"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 142,
                "end": 149,
                "text": "Hadrian"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 88,
                "end": 106,
                "text": "Knights of Elysium"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "They set a hologram in front of her to watch the execution of Theodora and Servilla au Arcos, as well as her Lionguard, and other people who were likely going to vote for her.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 62,
                "end": 70,
                "text": "Theodora"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 75,
                "end": 92,
                "text": "Servilla au Arcos"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 109,
                "end": 118,
                "text": "Lionguard"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "As Aja and the not-so-loyal Tactus walk in from Lorn's estate, they not only meet the Howler's but also see that Darrow obviously knew of the ambush, making it seem like Arcos warned his Student.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 3,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Aja"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 28,
                "end": 34,
                "text": "Tactus"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 48,
                "end": 54,
                "text": "Lorn's"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 86,
                "end": 94,
                "text": "Howler's"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 113,
                "end": 119,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 170,
                "end": 175,
                "text": "Arcos"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Mustang enters, revealing just how close she has gotten with House Lune.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 7,
                "text": "Mustang"
            },
            {
                "label": "PLANET",
                "start": 61,
                "end": 71,
                "text": "House Lune"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "He also tells them about how some ships went missing in the Kuiper Belt, and years later one of the Ascommani was seen.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "LOC",
                "start": 60,
                "end": 71,
                "text": "Kuiper Belt"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 100,
                "end": 109,
                "text": "Ascommani"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Dancer is alive and his face appears and the old Red assures Darrow that his family is safe.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Dancer"
            },
            {
                "label": "CASTE",
                "start": 49,
                "end": 52,
                "text": "Red"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 61,
                "end": 67,
                "text": "Darrow"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Darrow tells them all that he will wait for the Republic and his wife to send aid, and orders that they share their supplies with the civilians, despite the fact that it won't last a week if they do, as per Thraxa's argument.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 48,
                "end": 56,
                "text": "Republic"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 207,
                "end": 215,
                "text": "Thraxa's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Virginia realizes then that Lilath is the Syndicate Queen.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 8,
                "text": "Virginia"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 28,
                "end": 34,
                "text": "Lilath"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 42,
                "end": 57,
                "text": "Syndicate Queen"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Kavax, who is still healing, opts to go for a swim instead of going to the Citadel for the voting as he doesn't like to be there without Niobe.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 5,
                "text": "Kavax"
            },
            {
                "label": "LOC",
                "start": 75,
                "end": 82,
                "text": "Citadel"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 137,
                "end": 142,
                "text": "Niobe"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "His last opponent, Karnus au Bellona- brother to Julian and Cassius from Darrow's days at the Institute-is left with only one ship.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 19,
                "end": 36,
                "text": "Karnus au Bellona"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 49,
                "end": 55,
                "text": "Julian"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 60,
                "end": 67,
                "text": "Cassius"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 73,
                "end": 81,
                "text": "Darrow's"
            },
            {
                "label": "MISC",
                "start": 94,
                "end": 103,
                "text": "Institute"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "In a secret meeting, Glirastes explains why he sided with Darrow and at first is not willing to help Lysander, but when Lysander lies to him about seeing Tyche go down, it convinces Glirastes to side with Lysander.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 21,
                "end": 30,
                "text": "Glirastes"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 58,
                "end": 64,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 101,
                "end": 109,
                "text": "Lysander"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 120,
                "end": 128,
                "text": "Lysander"
            },
            {
                "label": "LOC",
                "start": 154,
                "end": 159,
                "text": "Tyche"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 182,
                "end": 191,
                "text": "Glirastes"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 205,
                "end": 213,
                "text": "Lysander"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Though Pax's conversation with Holiday is not detailed, it's likely he told her of his deeds with the Alltribe and his sacrifice.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 7,
                "end": 12,
                "text": "Pax's"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 31,
                "end": 38,
                "text": "Holiday"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 102,
                "end": 110,
                "text": "Alltribe"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Mustang briefs the remaining loyalists on what happened, that Augustus was taken by the Rage Knight Fitchner and the Morning Knight Cassius, but only after Nero killed the Hearth Knight.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 7,
                "text": "Mustang"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 62,
                "end": 70,
                "text": "Augustus"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 88,
                "end": 99,
                "text": "Rage Knight"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 100,
                "end": 108,
                "text": "Fitchner"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 117,
                "end": 131,
                "text": "Morning Knight"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 132,
                "end": 139,
                "text": "Cassius"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 156,
                "end": 160,
                "text": "Nero"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 172,
                "end": 185,
                "text": "Hearth Knight"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Virginia gives Theodora the order to turn him into a Splinter, Theodora's elite assassins.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 8,
                "text": "Virginia"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 15,
                "end": 23,
                "text": "Theodora"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 53,
                "end": 61,
                "text": "Splinter"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "The Abomination threatens to use the psychospikes on Sevro's mind before erasing it all together.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 4,
                "end": 15,
                "text": "Abomination"
            },
            {
                "label": "TECH",
                "start": 37,
                "end": 49,
                "text": "psychospikes"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 53,
                "end": 60,
                "text": "Sevro's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Niobe is headed to Mars to rendezvous with their house fleets.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 5,
                "text": "Niobe"
            },
            {
                "label": "PLANET",
                "start": 19,
                "end": 23,
                "text": "Mars"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "But Virginia's main purpose is to get the Optimate Party to convince enough voters to get her a Forum and the power over the defense fleets so she can aid Darrow.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 4,
                "end": 14,
                "text": "Virginia's"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 42,
                "end": 56,
                "text": "Optimate Party"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 155,
                "end": 161,
                "text": "Darrow"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "They are all tortured by the Gorgons and have lost their hair from the radiation off the Ladon.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 29,
                "end": 36,
                "text": "Gorgons"
            },
            {
                "label": "LOC",
                "start": 89,
                "end": 94,
                "text": "Ladon"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "As the celebrations go on through the night, Atalantia and Lysander have sex in her meditation chamber in the Annihilo.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 45,
                "end": 54,
                "text": "Atalantia"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 59,
                "end": 67,
                "text": "Lysander"
            },
            {
                "label": "VEHICLE",
                "start": 110,
                "end": 118,
                "text": "Annihilo"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "They go to one of the houses, where a red, Cormac O'Vadros, lives with his daughter, Brea, and son, Alred.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "CASTE",
                "start": 38,
                "end": 41,
                "text": "red"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 43,
                "end": 58,
                "text": "Cormac O'Vadros"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 85,
                "end": 89,
                "text": "Brea"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 100,
                "end": 105,
                "text": "Alred"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "The plan is for him to detonate a radium bomb at an upcoming gala at which all the Gold leaders across the Society will be, killing nearly every Gold of note.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "CASTE",
                "start": 83,
                "end": 87,
                "text": "Gold"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 107,
                "end": 114,
                "text": "Society"
            },
            {
                "label": "CASTE",
                "start": 145,
                "end": 149,
                "text": "Gold"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Rhone is later taken by some of the Rising soldiers, but Cicero and some of his men find them.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 5,
                "text": "Rhone"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 36,
                "end": 42,
                "text": "Rising"
            },
            {
                "label": "PER",
                "start": 57,
                "end": 63,
                "text": "Cicero"
