[
    {
        "text": "When they finally arrive at Tyche, Darrow realizes that Orion defied his order to keep the Storm God level to a minimum and has already destroyed much of the city and killed millions, Golds and civilians alike.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 28,
                "end": 33,
                "text": "Tyche"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 35,
                "end": 41,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 56,
                "end": 61,
                "text": "Orion"
            },
            {
                "label": "Technology",
                "start": 91,
                "end": 100,
                "text": "Storm God"
            },
            {
                "label": "Caste",
                "start": 184,
                "end": 189,
                "text": "Golds"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "On the day of the voting, Sevro leaves for Earth with fifty thousand of Virginia's men and Darrow's Seventh Legion, where they believe the Syndicate Queen to be, to kill her.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 26,
                "end": 31,
                "text": "Sevro"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 43,
                "end": 48,
                "text": "Earth"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 72,
                "end": 82,
                "text": "Virginia's"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 91,
                "end": 99,
                "text": "Darrow's"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 100,
                "end": 114,
                "text": "Seventh Legion"
            },
            {
                "label": "Rank",
                "start": 139,
                "end": 154,
                "text": "Syndicate Queen"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "The Battle of the Ladon is over, but all the major cities of Helios are now lost and millions of Darrow's men are either dead or missing, along with millions of the citizens of Heliopolis.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Event",
                "start": 4,
                "end": 23,
                "text": "Battle of the Ladon"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 61,
                "end": 67,
                "text": "Helios"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 97,
                "end": 105,
                "text": "Darrow's"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 177,
                "end": 187,
                "text": "Heliopolis"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Now, outlawed by the very Republic he founded, he wages a rogue war on Mercury in hope that he can still salvage the dream of Eo.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 26,
                "end": 34,
                "text": "Republic"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 71,
                "end": 78,
                "text": "Mercury"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 126,
                "end": 128,
                "text": "Eo"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "On their way there, Pax tells them of the theory of a group of Obsidians who escaped the genocide and cultural reengineering of their people - the Ascomanni, and how there might be a central force who leads them named Volsung the Taker.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 20,
                "end": 23,
                "text": "Pax"
            },
            {
                "label": "Caste",
                "start": 63,
                "end": 72,
                "text": "Obsidians"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 147,
                "end": 156,
                "text": "Ascomanni"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 218,
                "end": 235,
                "text": "Volsung the Taker"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "As Ajax prepares his legion, the Iron Leopards, for the battle, he lets them know they are not going to assist Scorpio au Votum to take Tyche as agreed upon by Atalantia, but they are going to take Heliopolis instead, much to Lysander's disappointment.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 3,
                "end": 7,
                "text": "Ajax"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 33,
                "end": 46,
                "text": "Iron Leopards"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 111,
                "end": 127,
                "text": "Scorpio au Votum"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 136,
                "end": 141,
                "text": "Tyche"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 160,
                "end": 169,
                "text": "Atalantia"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 198,
                "end": 208,
                "text": "Heliopolis"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 226,
                "end": 236,
                "text": "Lysander's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Sefi then tells them that Virginia was killed in the coup, as well as the archGovernor of Mars, and that Sevro has been captured on Earth.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 4,
                "text": "Sefi"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 26,
                "end": 34,
                "text": "Virginia"
            },
            {
                "label": "Profession",
                "start": 74,
                "end": 86,
                "text": "archGovernor"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 90,
                "end": 94,
                "text": "Mars"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 105,
                "end": 110,
                "text": "Sevro"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 132,
                "end": 137,
                "text": "Earth"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "He's greeted by an Obsidian shaman named Ozgard who tells him that they killed the Syndicate men after them.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Caste",
                "start": 19,
                "end": 27,
                "text": "Obsidian"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 41,
                "end": 47,
                "text": "Ozgard"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 83,
                "end": 92,
                "text": "Syndicate"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "On the ship, they find that the Obsidians living there had come from Mercury, when Cadus Harnassus had released half the fleet back to Luna.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Caste",
                "start": 32,
                "end": 41,
                "text": "Obsidians"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 69,
                "end": 76,
                "text": "Mercury"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 83,
                "end": 98,
                "text": "Cadus Harnassus"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 135,
                "end": 139,
                "text": "Luna"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "After he meets alone with Atalantia, she, along with Ajax and Kalindora, as well as the Primuses of House Carthii, House Votum, and House Falthe via hologram.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 26,
                "end": 35,
                "text": "Atalantia"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 53,
                "end": 57,
                "text": "Ajax"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 62,
                "end": 71,
                "text": "Kalindora"
            },
            {
                "label": "Rank",
                "start": 88,
                "end": 96,
                "text": "Primuses"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 100,
                "end": 113,
                "text": "House Carthii"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 115,
                "end": 126,
                "text": "House Votum"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 132,
                "end": 144,
                "text": "House Falthe"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "She gets news that Sevro has killed the Duke of Heads, the chief assassin of the Syndicate, as Sevro has been on a killing spree on orders of his wife, Victra, due to their kidnapped daughter, Electra.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 19,
                "end": 24,
                "text": "Sevro"
            },
            {
                "label": "Rank",
                "start": 40,
                "end": 53,
                "text": "Duke of Heads"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 81,
                "end": 90,
                "text": "Syndicate"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 95,
                "end": 100,
                "text": "Sevro"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 152,
                "end": 158,
                "text": "Victra"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 193,
                "end": 200,
                "text": "Electra"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "When the Storm God is activated, Darrow's army intercepts one of the enemy's divisions and are able to take down several legions, as well as Primus Scorpio au Votum.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Technology",
                "start": 9,
                "end": 18,
                "text": "Storm God"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 33,
                "end": 41,
                "text": "Darrow's"
            },
            {
                "label": "Rank",
                "start": 141,
                "end": 147,
                "text": "Primus"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 148,
                "end": 164,
                "text": "Scorpio au Votum"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Sefi then tells Ephraim that she plans on taking the Cimmeria mines and needs the Skuggi to be ready.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 4,
                "text": "Sefi"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 16,
                "end": 23,
                "text": "Ephraim"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 53,
                "end": 61,
                "text": "Cimmeria"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 82,
                "end": 88,
                "text": "Skuggi"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "After he wins his match, Sefi scolds him, but he digresses, instead attempting to guilt Sefi for not only taking them in as hostages/wards, but also for leaving Darrow before he left for Venus in Iron Gold.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 25,
                "end": 29,
                "text": "Sefi"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 88,
                "end": 92,
                "text": "Sefi"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 161,
                "end": 167,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 187,
                "end": 192,
                "text": "Venus"
            },
            {
                "label": "MISC",
                "start": 196,
                "end": 205,
                "text": "Iron Gold"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "He meets Dago of Gamma, the infamous Helldiver from a rival tribe of his.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 9,
                "end": 13,
                "text": "Dago"
            },
            {
                "label": "Profession",
                "start": 37,
                "end": 46,
                "text": "Helldiver"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 17,
                "end": 22,
                "text": "Gamma"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Darrow tells them all that he will wait for the Republic and his wife to send aid, and orders that they share their supplies with the civilians, despite the fact that it won't last a week if they do, as per Thraxa's argument.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 48,
                "end": 56,
                "text": "Republic"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 207,
                "end": 215,
                "text": "Thraxa's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "However, he and those with him, including Thraxa au Telemanus, Alexandar au Arcos, Colloway xe Char, Tongueless, and his niece Rhonna, attempt a rescue of one of his most loyal, Orion xe Aquarii, from the ship the Blood Medusa.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 42,
                "end": 61,
                "text": "Thraxa au Telemanus"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 63,
                "end": 81,
                "text": "Alexandar au Arcos"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 83,
                "end": 99,
                "text": "Colloway xe Char"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 101,
                "end": 111,
                "text": "Tongueless"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 127,
                "end": 133,
                "text": "Rhonna"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 178,
                "end": 194,
                "text": "Orion xe Aquarii"
            },
            {
                "label": "Vehicle",
                "start": 214,
                "end": 226,
                "text": "Blood Medusa"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Virginia gives Theodora the order to turn him into a Splinter, Theodora's elite assassins.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 8,
                "text": "Virginia"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 15,
                "end": 23,
                "text": "Theodora"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 53,
                "end": 61,
                "text": "Splinter"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "He is brought to the training square, where he watches Electra in a sparring match between two groups of young Obsidians.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 55,
                "end": 62,
                "text": "Electra"
            },
            {
                "label": "Caste",
                "start": 111,
                "end": 120,
                "text": "Obsidians"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "We learn that Pax has been allowed to work on an old gravBike, thanks to Ephraim's convincing.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 14,
                "end": 17,
                "text": "Pax"
            },
            {
                "label": "Technology",
                "start": 53,
                "end": 61,
                "text": "gravBike"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 73,
                "end": 82,
                "text": "Ephraim's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Virginia, upon meeting with Regulus ag Sun, finds herself being extorted by the Silvers' common interest federation, the Zenith Ring, with Brittania ag Krieg voicing out the proposals.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 8,
                "text": "Virginia"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 28,
                "end": 42,
                "text": "Regulus ag Sun"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 80,
                "end": 87,
                "text": "Silvers"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 121,
                "end": 132,
                "text": "Zenith Ring"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 139,
                "end": 157,
                "text": "Brittania ag Krieg"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "He also tells them about how some ships went missing in the Kuiper Belt, and years later one of the Ascommani was seen.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 60,
                "end": 71,
                "text": "Kuiper Belt"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 100,
                "end": 109,
                "text": "Ascommani"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Darrow is on Mercury looking at what's left of his army, over three thousand injured and no longer able to fight.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 13,
                "end": 20,
                "text": "Mercury"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Rhonna brings him an enemy in Fulminata uniform, but when they reveal his face, he knows it's Screwface, who was carved to go undercover in Atalantia's army.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Rhonna"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 30,
                "end": 39,
                "text": "Fulminata"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 94,
                "end": 103,
                "text": "Screwface"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 140,
                "end": 151,
                "text": "Atalantia's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Darrow makes live Operation Tartarus.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "MISC",
                "start": 18,
                "end": 36,
                "text": "Operation Tartarus"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Atalantia at first seems to reject having the Rim's help, but with some convincing, she agrees.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 9,
                "text": "Atalantia"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 46,
                "end": 51,
                "text": "Rim's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "As Daxo tries to protect Virginia and give her a way to escape the Citadel, he is also killed.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 3,
                "end": 7,
                "text": "Daxo"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 25,
                "end": 33,
                "text": "Virginia"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 67,
                "end": 74,
                "text": "Citadel"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Lysander then tells them of a Storm God, which only he in the group knows about.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 8,
                "text": "Lysander"
            },
            {
                "label": "Technology",
                "start": 30,
                "end": 39,
                "text": "Storm God"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "It wasn't until Octavia had sent Atlas au Raa on his mission to Pluto that the name Volsung was thought of again as Atlas had lost all but two ships early in the mission.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 16,
                "end": 23,
                "text": "Octavia"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 33,
                "end": 45,
                "text": "Atlas au Raa"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 64,
                "end": 69,
                "text": "Pluto"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 84,
                "end": 91,
                "text": "Volsung"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 116,
                "end": 121,
                "text": "Atlas"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "They are finally able to destroy the Storm God, but when Darrow and his men reach them, they are beaten easily, with Kalindora losing an arm, and Lysander having part of his face burned.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Technology",
                "start": 37,
                "end": 46,
                "text": "Storm God"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 57,
                "end": 63,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 117,
                "end": 126,
                "text": "Kalindora"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 146,
                "end": 154,
                "text": "Lysander"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Niobe is headed to Mars to rendezvous with their house fleets.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 5,
                "text": "Niobe"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 19,
                "end": 23,
                "text": "Mars"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "But Virginia's main purpose is to get the Optimate Party to convince enough voters to get her a Forum and the power over the defense fleets so she can aid Darrow.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 4,
                "end": 14,
                "text": "Virginia's"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 42,
                "end": 56,
                "text": "Optimate Party"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 155,
                "end": 161,
                "text": "Darrow"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "They arrive at Heliopolis only to find it being sieged by Ajax's men.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 15,
                "end": 25,
                "text": "Heliopolis"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 58,
                "end": 64,
                "text": "Ajax's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Lysander au Lune, the heir in exile, has returned to the Core.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 16,
                "text": "Lysander au Lune"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 57,
                "end": 61,
                "text": "Core"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Virginia realizes then that Lilath is the Syndicate Queen.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 8,
                "text": "Virginia"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 28,
                "end": 34,
                "text": "Lilath"
            },
            {
                "label": "Rank",
                "start": 42,
                "end": 57,
                "text": "Syndicate Queen"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "They hypothesize that Publius is the one collaborating with the Syndicate Queen.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 22,
                "end": 29,
                "text": "Publius"
            },
            {
                "label": "Rank",
                "start": 64,
                "end": 79,
                "text": "Syndicate Queen"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Ephraim wakes to find himself on Mars, along with Pax and Electra.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 7,
                "text": "Ephraim"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 33,
                "end": 37,
                "text": "Mars"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 50,
                "end": 53,
                "text": "Pax"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 58,
                "end": 65,
                "text": "Electra"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Kavax, who is still healing, opts to go for a swim instead of going to the Citadel for the voting as he doesn't like to be there without Niobe.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 5,
                "text": "Kavax"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 75,
                "end": 82,
                "text": "Citadel"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 137,
                "end": 142,
                "text": "Niobe"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Ephraim is required to attend the Kjrdakan, a war ritual performed before important battles, as aefe, a planner, which means that Sefi has accepted his plan, and not that of Valdir.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 7,
                "text": "Ephraim"
            },
            {
                "label": "Ritual/Holiday",
                "start": 34,
                "end": 42,
                "text": "Kjrdakan"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 130,
                "end": 134,
                "text": "Sefi"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 174,
                "end": 180,
                "text": "Valdir"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Publius and the Vox Populi shout tyranny and it becomes a coup, with many people and senators killed.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 7,
                "text": "Publius"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 16,
                "end": 26,
                "text": "Vox Populi"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "When it's time for the attack on Cimmeria, Ephraim, high on eating some of Ozgard's spirit berries, joins in the fray, holding a mop he hallucinated as a rifle.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 33,
                "end": 41,
                "text": "Cimmeria"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 43,
                "end": 50,
                "text": "Ephraim"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 75,
                "end": 83,
                "text": "Ozgard's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Darrow then gathers up the reliable veterans there and tells them of his plan of how to annihilate Atalantia and Atlas, and how they're his \"insurance policy\", under the name Operation Tartarus.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 99,
                "end": 108,
                "text": "Atalantia"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 113,
                "end": 118,
                "text": "Atlas"
            },
            {
                "label": "MISC",
                "start": 175,
                "end": 193,
                "text": "Operation Tartarus"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "They are now on Mars, and as Ephraim asks for zoladone when he awakes, Pax, who is there holding Trigg ti Nakamura's engagement ring, denies him the drug, knowing his addiction to it.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 16,
                "end": 20,
                "text": "Mars"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 29,
                "end": 36,
                "text": "Ephraim"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 71,
                "end": 74,
                "text": "Pax"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 97,
                "end": 116,
                "text": "Trigg ti Nakamura's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Unfortunately, when they reach it in painstaking effort, even while being aided by Cicero au Votum's Scorpian Legion, Seraphina is killed by an flyaway rail slug.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 83,
                "end": 100,
                "text": "Cicero au Votum's"
            },
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 101,
                "end": 116,
                "text": "Scorpian Legion"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 118,
                "end": 127,
                "text": "Seraphina"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Once they land on the ship, the Love Knight, Kalindora au San, who Lysander thought dead, and Ajax meet them skeptically.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Rank",
                "start": 32,
                "end": 43,
                "text": "Love Knight"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 45,
                "end": 61,
                "text": "Kalindora au San"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 67,
                "end": 75,
                "text": "Lysander"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 94,
                "end": 98,
                "text": "Ajax"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "When Diomedes and Seraphina are brought in, they explain Darrow's involvement in the Ganymede Dockyard destruction and of the death of their father, Romulus au Raa, and offer their aid to help in this war.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 5,
                "end": 13,
                "text": "Diomedes"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 18,
                "end": 27,
                "text": "Seraphina"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 57,
                "end": 65,
                "text": "Darrow's"
            },
            {
                "label": "Location",
                "start": 85,
                "end": 102,
                "text": "Ganymede Dockyard"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 149,
                "end": 164,
                "text": "Romulus au Raa,"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Harnassus, Thraxa, and Screwface discuss what to do next.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 9,
                "text": "Harnassus"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 11,
                "end": 17,
                "text": "Thraxa"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 23,
                "end": 32,
                "text": "Screwface"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Sefi proposes a deal with Ephraim.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 4,
                "text": "Sefi"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 26,
                "end": 33,
                "text": "Ephraim"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "As Atalantia begins her Iron Rain, Darrow loses many of his men in the atomic bombs that go off around their area.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 3,
                "end": 12,
                "text": "Atalantia"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 35,
                "end": 41,
                "text": "Darrow"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "When asked to join in the Iron Rain they have planned, Diomedes tells Atalantia he cannot join as that is not what he's there for, but Seraphina requests to join in his place, despite her brother's disapproval.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 55,
                "end": 63,
                "text": "Diomedes"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 70,
                "end": 79,
                "text": "Atalantia"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 135,
                "end": 144,
                "text": "Seraphina"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "All three of them are sequestered onto a shuttle to fly them to an old cruise vessel called the Heart of Venus.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Vehicle",
                "start": 96,
                "end": 110,
                "text": "Heart of Venus"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Lysander, who had just been hit and berated by Ajax moments prior for allowing himself to be ward to Cassius, also states his desire to join the Iron Rain, alongside Ajax.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 8,
                "text": "Lysander"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 47,
                "end": 51,
                "text": "Ajax"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 101,
                "end": 108,
                "text": "Cassius"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 166,
                "end": 170,
                "text": "Ajax"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "To confirm his loyalty to her, she has Sevro question the Duke without killing him, he does so, with the Duke unwillingly revealing his secrets through holoimages, including several images of Dancer O'Faran and him being intimate, due to the psychospikes she used on him.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 39,
                "end": 44,
                "text": "Sevro"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 58,
                "end": 62,
                "text": "Duke"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 105,
                "end": 109,
                "text": "Duke"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 192,
                "end": 206,
                "text": "Dancer O'Faran"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Pax leaves, and Electra yells at Sefi, blaming her for what has happened, and stalks off as well.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 3,
                "text": "Pax"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 16,
                "end": 23,
                "text": "Electra"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 33,
                "end": 37,
                "text": "Sefi"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Ephraim tells her they will be.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 7,
                "text": "Ephraim"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Despite Quicksilver's position and prior aid from his company, Virginia denies their proposals and she demands their votes instead.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 8,
                "end": 21,
                "text": "Quicksilver's"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 63,
                "end": 71,
                "text": "Virginia"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "But things go awry as soon as the Forum begins.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "MISC",
                "start": 34,
                "end": 39,
                "text": "Forum"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Though they are successful in rescuing Orion, it's obvious she has endured torture.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 39,
                "end": 44,
                "text": "Orion"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Lysander tells him of how he had become a ward to Cassius, and of Cassius' death and the whereabouts of his body.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 8,
                "text": "Lysander"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 50,
                "end": 57,
                "text": "Cassius"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 66,
                "end": 73,
                "text": "Cassius"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "As he's about to voice his vote for Virginia, he collapses, having been poisoned, and dies.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 36,
                "end": 44,
                "text": "Virginia"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Dancer agrees to side with Virginia.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Dancer"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 27,
                "end": 35,
                "text": "Virginia"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Darrow knows there's no escape, and Harnassus suggests surrender, thinking that though they will be tortured to death at least some of the civilians will survive.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Darrow"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 36,
                "end": 45,
                "text": "Harnassus"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "As alliances shift, break, and re-formâ€”and power is seized, lost, and reclaimedâ€”every player is at risk in a game of conquest that could turn the Rising into a new Dark Age.[5]",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Organization",
                "start": 146,
                "end": 152,
                "text": "Rising"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "They test Lysander to see if it's really him, and once it's confirmed, Ajax makes an effort to show his dislike of Diomedes and Seraphina.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 10,
                "end": 18,
                "text": "Lysander"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 71,
                "end": 75,
                "text": "Ajax"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 115,
                "end": 123,
                "text": "Diomedes"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 128,
                "end": 137,
                "text": "Seraphina"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Ephraim shows his confidence in his plan by making a blood wager.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 7,
                "text": "Ephraim"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "During the ritual, Valdir shows his displeasure and voices his anger, stating that Ephraim's plan will fail.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 19,
                "end": 25,
                "text": "Valdir"
            },
            {
                "label": "Person",
                "start": 83,
                "end": 92,
                "text": "Ephraim's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "She shows her skill as her team wins.",
        "mentions": []
    },
    {
        "text": "When he comes to again, he realizes that his injuries have been taken care of and his right leg has been replaced for a stronger one.",
        "mentions": []
    },
    {
        "text": "He puts her body with all the other bodies that were retrieved from the water.",
        "mentions": []
    },
    {
        "text": "And then teaches them how to lie by playing karachi, a card game which is presumably a game of skills and technique, much like poker.",
        "mentions": []
    }
]