[
    {
        "text": "Obi-Wan arrives in Pau City on Utapau, and begins his search for General Grievous, riding a varactyl named Boga.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 7,
                "text": "Obi-Wan"
            },
            {
                "label": "LOCATION",
                "start": 19,
                "end": 27,
                "text": "Pau City"
            },
            {
                "label": "PLANET",
                "start": 31,
                "end": 37,
                "text": "Utapau"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 65,
                "end": 72,
                "text": "General"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 73,
                "end": 81,
                "text": "Grievous"
            },
            {
                "label": "CREATURE",
                "start": 92,
                "end": 100,
                "text": "varactyl"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 107,
                "end": 111,
                "text": "Boga"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "A brief scuffle with stormtroopers and henchmen sent by Jabba ensues, and the Falcon escapes Imperial Star-Destroyers over Tatooine and sets a course to Alderaan, unaware that the Death Star has just arrived there as well.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 56,
                "end": 61,
                "text": "Jabba"
            },
            {
                "label": "SPACECRAFT",
                "start": 78,
                "end": 84,
                "text": "Falcon"
            },
            {
                "label": "SPACECRAFT",
                "start": 93,
                "end": 117,
                "text": "Imperial Star-Destroyers"
            },
            {
                "label": "PLANET",
                "start": 123,
                "end": 131,
                "text": "Tatooine"
            },
            {
                "label": "PLANET",
                "start": 153,
                "end": 161,
                "text": "Alderaan"
            },
            {
                "label": "WEAPON",
                "start": 180,
                "end": 190,
                "text": "Death Star"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Aboard the Death Star, Cassio Tagge argues with Conan Antonio Motti about the stations vulnerability to the rebels and points out that the rebellion has been gaining support within the imperial senate.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "WEAPON",
                "start": 11,
                "end": 21,
                "text": "Death Star"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 23,
                "end": 35,
                "text": "Cassio Tagge"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 48,
                "end": 67,
                "text": "Conan Antonio Motti"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 185,
                "end": 200,
                "text": "imperial senate"
            },
            {
                "label": "GPE",
                "start": 139,
                "end": 148,
                "text": "rebellion"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Upon finding the location of the Resistance base, the Starkiller begins draining the power of the sun to destroy D'Qar.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 33,
                "end": 43,
                "text": "Resistance"
            },
            {
                "label": "WEAPON",
                "start": 54,
                "end": 64,
                "text": "Starkiller"
            },
            {
                "label": "PLANET",
                "start": 113,
                "end": 118,
                "text": "D'Qar"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Hoping that the stolen plans can save her people and restore freedom to the galaxy, Princess Leia Organa, who is in custody of the plans, attempts to race home aboard the Tantive IV.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "SPACECRAFT",
                "start": 171,
                "end": 181,
                "text": "Tantive IV"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 93,
                "end": 104,
                "text": "Leia Organa"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 84,
                "end": 92,
                "text": "Princess"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Back aboard the Finalizer, Lieutenant Dopheld Mitaka informs Kylo Ren that the droid escaped on a stolen freighter and that it was aided by the deserter FN-2187.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "SPACECRAFT",
                "start": 16,
                "end": 25,
                "text": "Finalizer"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 27,
                "end": 37,
                "text": "Lieutenant"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 38,
                "end": 52,
                "text": "Dopheld Mitaka"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 61,
                "end": 69,
                "text": "Kylo Ren"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 153,
                "end": 160,
                "text": "FN-2187"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "In the Chancellor's office within the Imperial Senate Building, Yoda confronts Palpatine.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 7,
                "end": 19,
                "text": "Chancellor's"
            },
            {
                "label": "VEHICLE",
                "start": 38,
                "end": 62,
                "text": "Imperial Senate Building"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 64,
                "end": 68,
                "text": "Yoda"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 79,
                "end": 88,
                "text": "Palpatine"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Obi-Wan continues to chase General Grievous on Utapau.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 7,
                "text": "Obi-Wan"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 27,
                "end": 34,
                "text": "General"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 35,
                "end": 43,
                "text": "Grievous"
            },
            {
                "label": "PLANET",
                "start": 47,
                "end": 53,
                "text": "Utapau"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Senator Bail Organa arrives at the flaming Temple to witness the slaughter of a young Padawan named Zett Jukassa by a squad of troopers led by Commander Appo.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 7,
                "text": "Senator"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 8,
                "end": 19,
                "text": "Bail Organa"
            },
            {
                "label": "LOCATION",
                "start": 43,
                "end": 49,
                "text": "Temple"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 86,
                "end": 93,
                "text": "Padawan"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 100,
                "end": 112,
                "text": "Zett Jukassa"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 143,
                "end": 152,
                "text": "Commander"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 153,
                "end": 157,
                "text": "Appo"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Windu declares Sidious has lost, but the Sith Lord then unleashes a torrent of Force lightning.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 5,
                "text": "Windu"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 15,
                "end": 22,
                "text": "Sidious"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 41,
                "end": 50,
                "text": "Sith Lord"
            },
            {
                "label": "MISC",
                "start": 79,
                "end": 94,
                "text": "Force lightning"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Princess Leia Organa urges Han to stay with the Rebels.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 8,
                "text": "Princess"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 9,
                "end": 20,
                "text": "Leia Organa"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 27,
                "end": 30,
                "text": "Han"
            },
            {
                "label": "GPE",
                "start": 48,
                "end": 54,
                "text": "Rebels"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Kenobi hopes to instead warn any surviving Jedi to stay away from the Temple.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Kenobi"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 43,
                "end": 47,
                "text": "Jedi"
            },
            {
                "label": "LOCATION",
                "start": 70,
                "end": 76,
                "text": "Temple"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Yoda says they must destroy the Sith, but Obi-Wan is reluctant to kill Anakin and wants to go after the Emperor instead.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 4,
                "text": "Yoda"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 32,
                "end": 36,
                "text": "Sith"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 42,
                "end": 49,
                "text": "Obi-Wan"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 71,
                "end": 77,
                "text": "Anakin"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 104,
                "end": 111,
                "text": "Emperor"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "At Starkiller Base, a planet converted into a superweapon, powered by draining the energy of a star, and capable of destroying star systems, Kylo Ren and General Hux are summoned by Supreme Leader Snoke, who appears as a large remote hologram projection.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "WEAPON",
                "start": 3,
                "end": 18,
                "text": "Starkiller Base"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 141,
                "end": 149,
                "text": "Kylo Ren"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 154,
                "end": 161,
                "text": "General"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 162,
                "end": 165,
                "text": "Hux"
            },
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 182,
                "end": 196,
                "text": "Supreme Leader"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 197,
                "end": 202,
                "text": "Snoke"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "He also tells Anakin that the Jedi Order wishes to overthrow the Republic and that if he has suspected it, Anakin must surely have sensed it.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 14,
                "end": 20,
                "text": "Anakin"
            },
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 30,
                "end": 40,
                "text": "Jedi Order"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 107,
                "end": 113,
                "text": "Anakin"
            },
            {
                "label": "GPE",
                "start": 65,
                "end": 73,
                "text": "Republic"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "At the Mustafarian Mining Complex, Obi-Wan and Vader battle in the conference room on the desk.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "LOCATION",
                "start": 7,
                "end": 33,
                "text": "Mustafarian Mining Complex"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 35,
                "end": 42,
                "text": "Obi-Wan"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 47,
                "end": 52,
                "text": "Vader"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Obi-Wan leaves on an eopie, heading to his exile in the Jundland Wastes.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 7,
                "text": "Obi-Wan"
            },
            {
                "label": "LOCATION",
                "start": 56,
                "end": 71,
                "text": "Jundland Wastes"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Anakin and Obi-Wan make their way through the flagship, using their lightsabers to fight through an army of droids.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Anakin"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 11,
                "end": 18,
                "text": "Obi-Wan"
            },
            {
                "label": "WEAPON",
                "start": 68,
                "end": 79,
                "text": "lightsabers"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "It is at this point that the first physical manifestation of the dark side in Vader begins to show itself, as his irises turn a pallid yellow, the rest of his eyes taking on a bright crimson hue.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "MISC",
                "start": 65,
                "end": 74,
                "text": "dark side"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 78,
                "end": 83,
                "text": "Vader"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "After taking the foodstuff, Rey heads to her home, a downed AT-AT, and prepares a meal for herself.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 28,
                "end": 31,
                "text": "Rey"
            },
            {
                "label": "VEHICLE",
                "start": 60,
                "end": 65,
                "text": "AT-AT"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "In front of him is the burned helmet of Vader, recovered from the funeral pyre on Endor.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 40,
                "end": 45,
                "text": "Vader"
            },
            {
                "label": "PLANET",
                "start": 82,
                "end": 87,
                "text": "Endor"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Abandoning the arm, Obi-Wan leaps onto a hovering mining platform below, with Vader pursuing him back up the lava river atop a collection droid.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 20,
                "end": 27,
                "text": "Obi-Wan"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 78,
                "end": 83,
                "text": "Vader"
            },
            {
                "label": "DROID",
                "start": 127,
                "end": 143,
                "text": "collection droid"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Although they initially believe themselves to be captured by the First Order, they soon meet their real captors: Han Solo and Chewbacca, the former owners of the ship.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "GPE",
                "start": 65,
                "end": 76,
                "text": "First Order"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 113,
                "end": 121,
                "text": "Han Solo"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 126,
                "end": 135,
                "text": "Chewbacca"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Enraged, Grievous repeatedly hits Obi-Wan and then picks up the helpless Jedi and throws him over the edge.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 9,
                "end": 17,
                "text": "Grievous"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 34,
                "end": 41,
                "text": "Obi-Wan"
            },
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 73,
                "end": 77,
                "text": "Jedi"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "He finds Grievous on the Tenth Level.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 9,
                "end": 17,
                "text": "Grievous"
            },
            {
                "label": "LOCATION",
                "start": 25,
                "end": 36,
                "text": "Tenth Level"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "The First Order, tipped off to BB-8's presence, arrives and attacks Maz Kanata's castle.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "GPE",
                "start": 4,
                "end": 15,
                "text": "First Order"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 31,
                "end": 36,
                "text": "BB-8'"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 68,
                "end": 80,
                "text": "Maz Kanata's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "On Coruscant, Anakin is praised for his heroics.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PLANET",
                "start": 3,
                "end": 12,
                "text": "Coruscant"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 14,
                "end": 20,
                "text": "Anakin"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "As the majority of the Senate screams their approval, PadmÃ© Amidala and Bail Organa, who are shocked at the result, simply look around and PadmÃ© can only remark \"So this is how liberty dies, with thunderous applause.\"",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 23,
                "end": 29,
                "text": "Senate"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 54,
                "end": 67,
                "text": "PadmÃ© Amidala"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 72,
                "end": 83,
                "text": "Bail Organa"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 139,
                "end": 144,
                "text": "PadmÃ©"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "The rathtars provide a distraction for Han and Chewie to escape, but one catches Finn and drags him around the freighter.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "CREATURE",
                "start": 4,
                "end": 12,
                "text": "rathtars"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 39,
                "end": 42,
                "text": "Han"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 47,
                "end": 53,
                "text": "Chewie"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 81,
                "end": 85,
                "text": "Finn"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Kylo grows even more livid, using the Force to pull the officer by his throat across the room in order to choke him with his bare hands, and asking him what girl it was.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 4,
                "text": "Kylo"
            },
            {
                "label": "MISC",
                "start": 38,
                "end": 43,
                "text": "Force"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Inside the main base, chaos reigns as General Hux has already fled, and the other officers rush to abandon the installation as well.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 38,
                "end": 45,
                "text": "General"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 46,
                "end": 49,
                "text": "Hux"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "He leaves Gunray until last, slicing the Neimoidian across the chest even as he pleads for his life.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 10,
                "end": 16,
                "text": "Gunray"
            },
            {
                "label": "SPECIES",
                "start": 41,
                "end": 51,
                "text": "Neimoidian"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Attempting to seek guidance from his grandfather, Darth Vader, Kylo Ren sits quietly in his meditation chamber.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "RANK",
                "start": 50,
                "end": 55,
                "text": "Darth"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 56,
                "end": 61,
                "text": "Vader"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 63,
                "end": 71,
                "text": "Kylo Ren"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Obi-Wan uses a Jedi Mind trick on the lead trooper, who lets them pass.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 7,
                "text": "Obi-Wan"
            },
            {
                "label": "MISC",
                "start": 15,
                "end": 30,
                "text": "Jedi Mind trick"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Finn arranges with Sidon Ithano and his first mate Quiggold that he will work as payment if they will fly him to the Outer Rim.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 4,
                "text": "Finn"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 19,
                "end": 31,
                "text": "Sidon Ithano"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 51,
                "end": 59,
                "text": "Quiggold"
            },
            {
                "label": "LOCATION",
                "start": 117,
                "end": 126,
                "text": "Outer Rim"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "After he ignites it, he cuts himself free and cuts off the attacking wampa's arm just in time, running out of the cave and escaping into the cold night of Hoth.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "CREATURE",
                "start": 69,
                "end": 76,
                "text": "wampa's"
            },
            {
                "label": "PLANET",
                "start": 155,
                "end": 159,
                "text": "Hoth"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "After escaping from the trash compactor, the group hurries back to the Millennium Falcon, hoping that Obi-Wan has successfully shut down the tractor beam.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "SPACECRAFT",
                "start": 71,
                "end": 88,
                "text": "Millennium Falcon"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 102,
                "end": 109,
                "text": "Obi-Wan"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "During the travel in hyperspace, the Falcon experiences a problem with its hyperdrive, but Rey demonstrates her knowledge of ships by bypassing the compressor and fixing the issue.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "SPACECRAFT",
                "start": 37,
                "end": 43,
                "text": "Falcon"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 91,
                "end": 94,
                "text": "Rey"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "The First Order tracks Finn to the settlement, and launches an airstrike in attempt to search for BB-8 and the map.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "GPE",
                "start": 4,
                "end": 15,
                "text": "First Order"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 23,
                "end": 27,
                "text": "Finn"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 98,
                "end": 102,
                "text": "BB-8"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "She also draws on her experience climbing through wrecked Imperial starships to make her way through the bowels of the installation's machinery.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "NORP",
                "start": 58,
                "end": 66,
                "text": "Imperial"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "He jumps into his landspeeder.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "VEHICLE",
                "start": 18,
                "end": 29,
                "text": "landspeeder"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Sidious, cackling with glee, tortures and blasts the shocked Windu out of the window, sending him plunging to his death hundreds of stories below.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 60,
                "end": 65,
                "text": "Windu"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "With the re-emergence of his father and Snoke's orders to kill him, Kylo feels an internal struggle within himself.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 40,
                "end": 47,
                "text": "Snoke's"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 68,
                "end": 72,
                "text": "Kylo"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Rey and Ren continue fighting: Ren has taken even more wounds, from Chewbacca, Finn, and Rey, but even so initially holds the advantage, drawing on his rage to ignore the pain.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 3,
                "text": "Rey"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 8,
                "end": 11,
                "text": "Ren"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 31,
                "end": 34,
                "text": "Ren"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 68,
                "end": 77,
                "text": "Chewbacca"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 79,
                "end": 83,
                "text": "Finn"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 89,
                "end": 92,
                "text": "Rey"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Enraged, Chewbacca, Rey, and Finn start firing at Ren and the stormtroopers.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 9,
                "end": 18,
                "text": "Chewbacca"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 20,
                "end": 23,
                "text": "Rey"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 29,
                "end": 33,
                "text": "Finn"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 50,
                "end": 53,
                "text": "Ren"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Obi-Wan feels guilt for failing Anakin & PadmÃ©'s happiness.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 31,
                "end": 37,
                "text": "Anakin"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 40,
                "end": 47,
                "text": "PadmÃ©'s"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Finn, Han, and Chewie volunteer to disable the base's defensive shield from the inside.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 4,
                "text": "Finn"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 6,
                "end": 9,
                "text": "Han"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 15,
                "end": 21,
                "text": "Chewie"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "They engage in an intense battle using their lightsabers and Force abilities.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "ORG",
                "start": 61,
                "end": 66,
                "text": "Force"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Kolar is the first to die, run through the chest and as Kolar's life is ending due to the wound, Sidious turns and slices Tiin's torso.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 5,
                "text": "Kolar"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 56,
                "end": 63,
                "text": "Kolar's"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 97,
                "end": 104,
                "text": "Sidious"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 122,
                "end": 128,
                "text": "Tiin's"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "He tells his story that he was a stormtrooper in the First Order.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "GPE",
                "start": 53,
                "end": 64,
                "text": "First Order"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Vader, mad with power, claims that they no longer have to run away and he can overthrow Palpatine so that the two of them can rule the galaxy together.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 85,
                "end": 94,
                "text": "Palpatine"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Obi-Wan intervenes and demands Vader to release PadmÃ©, but Vader still chokes her unconscious.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 30,
                "end": 35,
                "text": "Vader"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 47,
                "end": 52,
                "text": "PadmÃ©"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 58,
                "end": 63,
                "text": "Vader"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Upon realizing that the story was really about the droids' adventures and it was them leading things to Luke and Obi-Wan, etc.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 104,
                "end": 108,
                "text": "Luke"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 113,
                "end": 120,
                "text": "Obi-Wan"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "PadmÃ© also tells him Obi-Wan knew about them together, wanting to help them & begs him to run away with her to raise their child in peace.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 19,
                "end": 26,
                "text": "Obi-Wan"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Seeing this, Han, Chewbacca, Finn, and Rey try to create an opening by planting thermal detonators inside the base.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 13,
                "end": 16,
                "text": "Han"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 18,
                "end": 27,
                "text": "Chewbacca"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 29,
                "end": 33,
                "text": "Finn"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 39,
                "end": 42,
                "text": "Rey"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Windu also adds that if what Anakin says is true then Anakin will have gained his trust but for now, he wants Anakin to wait in the Council Chambers until he returns.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 5,
                "text": "Windu"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 29,
                "end": 35,
                "text": "Anakin"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 54,
                "end": 60,
                "text": "Anakin"
            },
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 110,
                "end": 116,
                "text": "Anakin"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "Anakin attempts to shoot the droids off, though succeeds only in blasting apart the wing of his former Master's vessel.",
        "mentions": [
            {
                "label": "PERSON",
                "start": 0,
                "end": 6,
                "text": "Anakin"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "text": "After securing the area, the remaining villagers are herded into the town square.",
        "mentions": []
    },
    {
        "text": "He is dressed in black armor, a face mask is sealed tightly, and his helmet is fitted.",
        "mentions": []
    },
    {
        "text": "He also explains that the war is almost over.",
        "mentions": []
    },
    {
        "text": "This is a scene with Darth Vader and another Imperial officer on the Death Star.",
        "mentions": []
    },
    {
        "text": "Revenge of the Sith was released in theaters on Thursday, May 19, 2005 (the same day that the first episode of the prequel trilogy The Phantom Menace was released in 1999), and premiered (out of competition) on the 2005 Cannes Festival May 15.",
        "mentions": []
    },
    {
        "text": "It is now three years after the events of A New Hope.",
        "mentions": []
    },
    {
        "text": "Biggs quietly tells Luke that he has decided to join the Rebellion against the Empire.",
        "mentions": []
    },
    {
        "text": "Deak, Windy, Camie, Fixer and Biggs all follow Luke outside to see the battle with Luke's macrobinoculars.",
        "mentions": []
    },
    {
        "text": "On November 12, 2019, the film was included with the launch of Disney+.",
        "mentions": []
    },
    {
        "text": "A boy and a girl are born.",
        "mentions": []
    },
    {
        "text": "The scene would have appeared between the scene where Han Solo encounters Jabba the Hutt in Docking Bay 94 (also cut), and the scene where Luke and Ben find the Millennium Falcon in Docking Bay 94.",
        "mentions": []
    },
    {
        "text": "This scene was to come in between the scene where C-3PO spots a distant Jawa sandcrawler in the desert, and the capture of R2-D2 by the Jawas in the canyon.",
        "mentions": []
    },
