'You are now an entity recognition model. Always answers as helpfully as possible.
These are the entity types you are tasked to identify:
PERSON: Person Name - Proper names of people, including droids, first names, last names, individual or family names, unique nicknames.
SPECIES: Species - Names of sentient alien species/races
PLANET: Planet - Name of a planet or star system.
LOC: Location - Name of any place that is not a planet. Often a city or geographical feature.
ORG: Organization - Names of companies, government agencies, educational institutions, military units
GPE: Geopolitical Entity - Names of governing bodies
NORP: Nationality, Other, Religion, Political - Derived/adjectival forms of GPE and Location names, as well as adjectival forms of named religions, heritage and political affiliation.
EVENT: Event - Events with proper names, such as specific wars, battles, or political landmarks.
WEAPON: Weapon - Any named armament specific to Star Wars, regardless of size - excludes generic items like ‘weapon,’ ‘cannon,’ etc
CREATURE: Creature - Any non-sentient creature/monster/animal native to the Star Wars universe
DROID: Droid Type - Name of a type or class or droid
VEHICLE: Vehicle type - Name of a type of class of vehicle
SPACECRAFT: Spacecraft name - Proper name of a specific instance of a vehicle capable of space travel
RANK: Rank/Title - Official signifiers of ranks, titles, positions, most typically military ranks or other signifiers of status within an organization. Excludes informal/familial titles.
MISC: Miscellaneous/Force - Other named entities, often generic references to the Force
Use these examples to train your tagging system:
After gaining Supreme Leader Snoke\'s permission to fire the Starkiller superweapon, Hux chooses the Hosnian system, which hosts the capital of the New Republic, Hosnian Prime, as well as the New Republic Defense Fleet, in order to demonstrate the power of the First Order in an attempt to wipe out the "illegitimate" government of the New Republic in one fell swoop.
{"entity": "Snoke\'s", "label": "PERSON"}
{"entity": "Supreme Leader", "label": "RANK"}
{"entity": "Starkiller", "label": "WEAPON"}
{"entity": "Hux", "label": "PERSON"}
{"entity": "Hosnian", "label": "PLANET"}
{"entity": "New Republic", "label": "GPE"}
{"entity": "Hosnian Prime,", "label": "PLANET"}
{"entity": "New Republic Defense Fleet", "label": "ORG"}
{"entity": "First Order", "label": "GPE"}
{"entity": "New Republic", "label": "GPE"}
Obi-Wan arrives in Pau City on Utapau, and begins his search for General Grievous, riding a varactyl named Boga.
{"entity": "Obi-Wan", "label": "PERSON"}
{"entity": "Pau City", "label": "LOCATION"}
{"entity": "Utapau", "label": "PLANET"}
{"entity": "General", "label": "RANK"}
{"entity": "Grievous", "label": "PERSON"}
{"entity": "varactyl", "label": "CREATURE"}
{"entity": "Boga", "label": "PERSON"}
A brief scuffle with stormtroopers and henchmen sent by Jabba ensues, and the Falcon escapes Imperial Star-Destroyers over Tatooine and sets a course to Alderaan, unaware that the Death Star has just arrived there as well.
{"entity": "Jabba", "label": "PERSON"}
{"entity": "Falcon", "label": "SPACECRAFT"}
{"entity": "Imperial Star-Destroyers", "label": "SPACECRAFT"}
{"entity": "Tatooine", "label": "PLANET"}
{"entity": "Alderaan", "label": "PLANET"}
{"entity": "Death Star", "label": "WEAPON"}
Anakin returns to the Jedi Temple and approaches Windu who tells Anakin that they have just been informed that Obi-Wan has destroyed General Grievous and so they are going to go to the Senate to ensure that Chancellor Palpatine gives back his emergency powers.
{"entity": "Anakin", "label": "PERSON"}
{"entity": "Jedi Temple", "label": "LOCATION"}
{"entity": "Windu", "label": "PERSON"}
{"entity": "Anakin", "label": "PERSON"}
{"entity": "Obi-Wan", "label": "PERSON"}
{"entity": "Grievous", "label": "PERSON"}
{"entity": "General", "label": "RANK"}
{"entity": "Senate", "label": "ORG"}
{"entity": "Chancellor", "label": "RANK"}
{"entity": "Palpatine", "label": "PERSON"}
Aboard the Death Star, Cassio Tagge argues with Conan Antonio Motti about the stations vulnerability to the rebels and points out that the rebellion has been gaining support within the imperial senate.
{"entity": "Death Star", "label": "WEAPON"}
{"entity": "Cassio Tagge", "label": "PERSON"}
{"entity": "Conan Antonio Motti", "label": "PERSON"}
{"entity": "imperial senate", "label": "ORG"}
{"entity": "rebellion", "label": "GPE"}
Please label all entities that fit these descriptions. Do NOT give any labels that are not in the above ontology